<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-adolph-luetgert</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87060190/1897-05-18/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Adolph+Luetgert</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Adolph L. Luet
              gerjl, a well known manufacturer vraa
              arrested yesterday afternoon on tho
              chargo of having murdered his wife.
              Luetgert made an assignment about 10
              days ago, and about tho same time Mrs.
              Luetgert disappeared. It was at first
              supposed that she had committed sui
              cide, as a result Of her husband's
              failnro.
              Tho river was dragged, but with no
              result, and for several days detectives
              have been working on tho murder
              theory. Tho police claim to have direct
              evidence that Luetgert klljed his wife
              in tho basement of his sausage factory
              in Diversoy street, and that her body
              was destroyed with the object of hiding,
              all traces of tho crime.
              Tho police will show, they say, that
              Luetgert persuaded his wife to accom
              pany him to his sansago factory on Aie
              evening of May 1 that upon gettiug
              into his building ho choked her to death
              or to insensibility that he then threw
              her into a vat containing a powerful
              acid, and completed his work by casting
              the body into an intonso firo.
              This is the direct chargo against tho
              prisoner. Tho main evidence in snp-
              Jiort of it aro two gold rings which be
              ouged to Mrs. Luetgort and which
              were found by the polico in a vat in tho
              sausage factory. Ono of tho rings
              found in tho vat was tho wedding ring
              of Mrs. Luetgert.
              On tho day following tho woman's
              disappearance Luetgert failed in busi
              ness, and tho sheriff took possession of
              the sausage factory. Luetgert endeav
              ored time and again to gain udmission
              to the factory but tho deputy sheriffs re
              fused to admit him. The polico claim
              that he desired to get into tho place for
              the purpose of removing all traces of tho
              crime. Ho did attempt to olean out
              tho vat in which the rings were found,
              but tho escape pipe was a few inches
              abovo the bottom of tho tank and the
              rings sank to tho bottom below tho level
              of the pipe.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063615/1897-07-20/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Adolph+Luetgert+wife&st=text&r=-0.252,-0.075,1.504,1.504,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82016014/1897-08-07/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Adolph+Luetgert+wife&st=text&r=-0.14,-0.064,1.28,1.28,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82016014/1897-08-07/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Adolph+Luetgert+wife&st=text&r=-0.14,-0.064,1.28,1.28,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Luetgert was calm and composed
              when he was brought into court and
              he had apparently been greatly re I
              freshed by Sundays respite from the
              daily court room ordeal Assistant
              States Attorney McEwan formally
              opened the case for the state Op the
              wall close to the jury box were hung
              large maps of the Luetgert sausage
              factory the Luetgert home and all the
              surroundings of the place where it is i
              charged the prisoner killed his wife
              and then destroyed her body The at il
              torney for the state began with the
              disappearance of Mrs Luetgert on May
              1 and next described the visit on May
              4 of Dietrich Blcknese brother of Mrs
              Luetgert when he called to see his sis
              ter and discovered that she had disap
              peared 
              Mr McE wan said it is the theory of
              the state that Mrs Luetgert accom
              panied her husband into the factory
              between 1036 and 11 celock About
              1030 her little son Louis returned from
              the circus and saw her sitting In the
              kitchen The conversation of the boy
              with his mother was interrupted by
              Luetgert who came in and ordered the
              boy to bed Before going to sleep the
              boy heard his father descending the
              back stairs toward the factory where
              he had slept for years Mr McEwan
              said it is cite theory of the state that
              Mrs Luetgert descended the stairs at
              the same tim andwent to the factory
              The boy did not hear her steps because
              she wore house slippers which made no
              noise Luetgert and his wife were seen
              in the alley in the rear of the house a
              few minutes later They were seen
              gong through a gate which led tb no
              place except the factory
              ALLEGED MOTIVE
              The alleged motive and operating
              I reason which actuated Luetgert ac
              cording to the theory of the state was
              then described Mr ileEwon said Luet
              gert despised hs wife He had treated
              her with violence as the evidence of
              the state will show He had no affection
              for her and lived alone in the factory
              There the attorney said he had been
              visited by other women Judge Vincent
              objected to this statement but Judge
              Tuthill overruled the objection Mr
              McEwan paid a witness would testify
              that he KUV Luetgetri choke his wife in
              the chicken house back of the resdence
              She said
              You need rot toll me as you did that
              man for I have no money
              This caused Luetgrert to say that she
              would rot be allowed to betray him
              I Then the afternoon session began
              the first witness called was Diedrich
              Bicknez brother of Mrs Luetgert He
              told the jury of his visit to the house
              of Luetgert on May 4 to see his sister
              There he met the sausage maker and
              talked with him for some time before
              he was informed that Mrs Luetgert
              had disappeared Bicknez said Luet
              gert told him he did not know what
              had become of his wife He had last
              seen her at S oclock the Saturday
              evening previous Luetgert said he did
              I not believe she had gone away with
              i some other man but thought she had
              wandered away The witness said he
              asked the prisoner what he had done
              to find his wife and was Informed that
              he had rot told the police of her dis
              appearance Instead he said he had
              paid two private detectives 5 each and
              they would do more than the police
              would accomplish
              I The witness said Luetgeri told him
              he had not looked to see if his wife
              had taken any clothing with her ex
              cept the dress she had on when he last
              saw her He had not visited any place
              or made any inquiries
              I I Bicknes told hyi story in i a simple
              I straightforward way that made him an
              impressive witness
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1897-08-31/ed-1/?sp=6&st=text</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Continued from Page I
              had gone to a circus on the evening of
              his mothers disappearance He re
              turned about 1030 and found his
              mother to whom he described what he
              had seen at the circus While engaged
              in this conversation he said his father
              entered the room and ordered him to
              I bed Later lIe said he heard his
              father descending the rear stairway in
              the direction of the sausage factory
              This portion of his testimony was
              identical with that given at the pre
              liminary and the habeas corpus hear
              ings
              But today he continued by saying
              that after he had been asleep for a
              long time he was suddenly awakened
              byhearing a rustling of skirts in his
              bedroom He called out Is that you
              father but his mothers voice replied
              I
              plied no it Is me
              The lad declared that he was sure
              that it was his mothers voice which
              replied to his query and he soon went
              tQ sleep
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059523/1897-10-01/ed-1/?sp=7&q=Adolph+Luetgert+wife&st=text&r=0.523,0.914,0.29,0.326,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059523/1897-10-01/ed-1/?sp=7&q=Adolph+Luetgert+wife&st=text&r=0.523,0.914,0.29,0.326,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>hhttps://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063952/1897-10-23/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Adolph+Luetgert+wife&st=text&r=0.29,0.43,0.184,0.207,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Last night Luetgert mndo the fol
              lowing statomunt under oath:
              "To tho Public Tho result of ny
              trinl Is a victory for mc becauso of the
              disagreement of tho Jury, but 1 nm
              very much disappointed nnd very
              much surprised thnt tho jury did nut
              bring in a verdict of not gulltv.
              "1 did not kill my wife, nnd do not
              know whoro she Is, but I nm sure thnt
              It is only a question of timo until hIio
              comes home.
              "I did not jjo vpon tho wltnoiw
              stnnil because my lnwyor. Judge Vln
              coiit, wns bitterly opposed to my do
              ing so, and W'iinsc- he ndvUed me it
              was not necessary. 1 nm grntoful tor
              the tremendous change In publio boh
              tiincnt In my favor, nnd time will
              demonstrate that I nm not only nn in
              nocent, but n very grievously wronged,
              mnn. Adoi.imi I LrirrnriiT."
              "Subscribed nnd sworn to before
              mo this Slst day of Octobor, A. 1).,
              1807. F. M. Suu.iVAX, Notary Public."
              "Yes, sir, wo will try him ngnlu,"
              said Suite's Attorney Dencon, whoit
              asked ns to probability of Luetgert
              being brought before tho court n sec
              ond tlmo. "When xve will get at him.
              however, Is something I cannot toll
              you now. We have had nine weeks of
              this, and I must have a couple of
              weeks' rest After that wo will look
              tho ground over and get our evidence
              together."
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85033781/1897-10-27/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Adolph+Luetgert+wife+witness&st=text&r=0.05,0.702,0.208,0.234,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>CRIME Of A CENTURY
              Review of the Celcb'ittd l.iot
              gert Murder Trial d
              Chicago.
              SCORES OF WITNESSES EXAMINED
              tate Wearfi a Net of Circumstantial Evi
              dence About the Prisoner Expert Teatl
              loony uu Hone Foil ml in the Middle Vat
              of the SauMtge Factory Allege! Appear
              ance or the MUliitf Woman In Varloin
              Place Perwoiiallty of the Prioner.
              Or the rJfiht of May 1 last Louisa
              Luetgert disappeared. At 8 o'clock
              Mary Siemmering. the servant girl, re
              tired for the night, leaving Mrs. Luet
              gert Etill about the house. A little later
              the boy Louis returned from a circus
              vhich had been exhibiting in the neigh
              borhood and found his mother sitting In
              a chair. It was then about 10 o'clock
              end he was sent to bed, having seen the
              last of his mother, perhaps forever. Mr.
              Luetgert came Into the house a little be
              fore the boy went to bed, and the latter
              left husband and wife together. At this
              roint the story diverges and the most
              erious trouble of A. L. Luetgert's life
              begins. At what hour Mrs. Luetgert
              left the house no one, save possibly her
              husband, knows. The following day
              Sunday members of the family knew
              that its mistress was gone. On the 17th
              day of May the climax came. The saus
              age maker, who had been almost a king
              among his neighbors, was dragged up
              the steps of the East Chicago avenue
              police station at about 2 o'clock In the
              afternoon.
              Luetgert's preliminary examination
              began before Justice Kersten on May
              22. Bickenese, Mrs. Luetgert's L. other,
              told of Luetgert's indifference, old
              Frank Bialk told how Luetgert had
              spent the night on which his wif dis
              appeared cooking something in the rrii
              die vat, and the police disclosed the
              rings. Mrs. Agatha Tosch, Luetgert's
              warm friend and proprietor of the sa
              loon which he patronized most, declared
              to the police she believed him guilty
              cf wife murder, and unexpectedly went
              on the stand and told how Luetgert had
              railed about his wife to her, and had
              eald he wished she were dead.
              The only person from whom the po
              lice could not extract a word was Lust
              gert himself. Sweatbox, persuasion,
              threats and coaxing had no effect on
              him.
              One Week to Get a Jnry.
              The trial was begun eight weeks ago,
              on Aug. 23. One hundred and forty ven
              Jremen had to be summoned, and one
              "week consumed before twelve Jurymen
              were secured. On Monday, Aug. 20,
              Diedrich Bicknese, the first witness for
              the prosecution, was put on the stand
              Louis Luetgert, the 12-year-old son
              cf the prisoner, was one of the state's
              earliest witnesses. He recited the oc
              currences of the night of May 1, and
              told a powerful story for the prosecu
              tion, on cross-examination there was a
              rurprise for the state. The boy an
              nounced that at 2 o'clock in the morn
              ing of May 2, when, according to the j
              ytate, Mrs. Luetger's body was being
              destroyed in the vat, he heard a "rust
              ling" in the house, and a voice which I
              he believed was his mother's. Young i
              Luetgert acknowledged he had suddenly
              recollected this in the office of Luetgert's
              attorneys, and the state flatly charged
              that Luetgert's attorneys had manufact
              ured the evidence.
              Luetgert's threats, his statement that
              he would like to cru?h his wife, and that
              he regreted calling a doctor for her
              when she was ill, that the "dead, rot
              ten boast would have croaKed," were re
              counted by Mrs. Agatha Tosch. Frank
              Bialk told of Luetgert's unexplained
              actions the night his wife vanished, and
              then the state disclosed how the potash
              came in the vat.
              Frank Odorofsky and Jacob Lavan
              dowsky, two laborers about the factory,
              told starring stories of breaking potash
              Into small pieces, burning their hands
              and faces, and putting it In the vat un
              der Luetgert's orders. They described
              the sticky, slimy stuff on the basement
              floor the morning after the alleged mur
              der, when Luetgert had partly flushed
              the vat by means of a hose.
              Had Hitter Quarrel.
              Neighbors and relatives of th Luet
              gerts testified to the bitter quarrels be
              tween them, and Luetgert's employes
              related how Mary Siemmering, his serv
              ant, had visited him at the factory at
              unseemly hours. It was known that
              when Luetgert sent old Frank Bialk to
              a distant drug store for Hunyadl water
              while he was busy at the vat, there were
              fifty bottles of Hunyadl water in the
              factory.
              Emma and Gottliebe Schimpke, two
              girls living across the street from the
              Luetgerts, went on the stand and told
              cf seeing Luetgert and his wife going
              In the direction of the factory at 10
              o'clock on the night of May 1. Luet
              gert's attorneys succeeded In frighten
              ing them on cross-examination. There
              was a second sensation when Nicholas
              Faber testified that on the night of May
              1 he had gone to Luetgert's house to ap
              ply for work at the factory, and that he
              also had seen Luetgert and his wife go
              ing down the alley toward the factory
              !oor.
              The gold rings, with Mrs. Luetgert's
              Initials, were regarded as the strongest
              vldence the state produced. Numer
              ous witnesses, some of whom had worn
              the rings, positively Identified them as
              Mrs, Luetgert's, and but one witness
              was ever produced who doubted their
              authenticity.
              The state began by showing the feel
              ing of Luetgert toward his wife. Then
              the prosecution traced her from the
              house on the night of May 1 almost to
              the door of the factory with her hus
              band. It was shown that the basement
              door was barred, and that Bialk, thdi
              only person In the factory that night,
              had been sent away at about the time
              It was charged the rnWder occurred.
              Hone Identified a Human.
              Odorofsky and Lavandowsky disclosed
              Luetgert had caused the furnace to be
              raked out the following day, and It was
              where these ashes were dumped that
              parts of the fragments of alleged hu
              man bone were discovered.
              A sesamoid bone and a metacarpal,
              badly mutilated by the fluid, and found
              In the middle vat by the police, were
              positively Identified as human by Dr.
              Dorsey, a curator at the Field Colum
              bian museum: Dr. George V. Bailer,
              working osteologist at the museum, and
              Dr. Howes, an articulator. Another
              fragment of bone from the heap
              where the furnace Takings were
              dumped was Identified as -part of a hu
              man t.kull. A badly mutilated bone from
              the engine room was Identified positive
              ly by Dr. I)or.y as rart of a human
              thigh bone, and from the size of these
              fragments the experts expressed the be
              lief they were from the same Individual,
              and that individual probably a woman.
              Luetgert's attorneys caused two en
              tire human bodies to be cftoked In the
              middle vat and rarte of several others,
              to see whether V'de Pta?h would de
              stroy them as the state claimed.
              Corsetmakers identified the steels
              found In the furnace raklngs as corset
              steels, and 'rom the bony fragments the
              experts lcVf'flcd the head cf a human
              rib, a seconu piece of thigh bone, and
              a fragment of a human toe.
              A to the Hone.
              William Charles, Luetgert's closest
              friend, positively stated he. had helped
              Luetgert dump four barrels of tallow
              and bones In the vat on the night of
              May 1 to make soap with, and other
              witnesses confirmed the claim of the
              defense that Luetgert was making soap
              on the night of May 1.
              Since Luetgert's arrest the claim has
              been made that Mrs. Luetgert has ap
              peared In at least 100 different cities,
              from Nebraska to New York city. Some
              of these were Investigated, and In ev
              ery case but one the defense's assertion
              was exploded. That was the defense's
              claim that Mrs. Luetgert was seen at
              Kenosha, and in the opinion of the state
              It was never shown Mrs. Luetgert was
              there. As many witnesses, and more
              reputable ones, saw the strange woman
              there and were sure she was not Mru.
              Luetgert.
              In all.over 200 witnesses testified dur
              ing the eight weeks of the trial. The
              total cost Is estimated at 118,000.
              Dlversey.
              Differ on Jlulnet Plan.
              Luetgert and his wife had widely dif
              ferent notions as to how large a saus
              age plant ought to be built. Luetgert
              had visions of a six-story building,
              with railroad tracks running to It and
              loaded cars at the doors. Mrs. Luetgert
              wished her husband to Invest $40,000 In
              the new plant and the balance of their
              savings In some other investment.
              Family Jan Increased.
              Last February Luetgert's factory
              closed down. When profits ceased to
              pile up Mrs. Luetgert's scoldings and
              the family Jars Increased. Mary Siem
              erlng had In the meantime come to live
              with the Luetgertfj. and Luetgert's fond
              ness for her, It V said, Increased the
              bitterness between him and his wife.
              Financial roi stared Luetgert in the
              face by the middle of April. The sausage-maker
              and his wife saw that the
              factory was almost certain to pass Into
              the hands of the sheriff, for note9 were
              falling due, there was no Income to pay
              them from, and butchers and market
              men who were In Luetgert's debt were
              unable to help him out of difficulty in
              the hard times. Mrs. Luetgert, who
              had seen her advice thrown to the winds,
              and her dire predictions all come true,
              lost no opportunity to scold her hus
              band for his folly. The reports of the
              Luetgert family disturbances Increased
              throughout the neighborhood and were
              the object of many conferences among
              Mra Luetgert's relatives.
              S17EABSHE ISSIHLESS
              First Sworn Statement Made by
              Adolph Luetgert, the Alleged
              Chicago Wife-Murderer.
              BRIEF DENIAL THAT HE IS GUILTY
              Did Not Kill III Wife and Doe N6t Know
              Where 'Site 1, lie Kay Uelleve She
              Will Yet lleappear Alive-Jury Fail to
              Agree, Declare Agreement Impolble
              aud I DUc barged Accused Mail Will
              Try to Get Out on Hail.
              Chicago, Oct. 22. The Associated Press
              last night obtained the one great feature
              missing in the famous Luetgert trial
              the sworn testimony cf the defendant
              himself, Adolph L. Luetgert. Standing
              last night In the gloomy Jail adjoining
              the grim-looking gray-stone court build
              ing in which his remarkable triaj had
              at last been brought to a finish, the burly
              sausage manufacturer capped the cli
              max of the extraordinary series of events
              which began with his bankruptcy and
              alleged frightful diabolism cf boiling his
              wife to death at midnight in a vat In his
              factory cellar. Closely following the
              final result of the trial which has at
              tracted world-wide attention, Luetgert
              made under oath a statement concerning
              the fearful crime charged against him,
              the first sworn statement of such a kind
              ever known In newspaper annals.
              Few If any of the curious prisoners
              and turnkeys who were' spectators had
              any inkling of what was taking place.
              Luetgert, the notary and the representa
              tive of the Associated Press conferred
              together for a few moments and then
              Luetgert without hesitation made affi
              davit and signed It In ink with the hand
              that Is alleged to have committed one of
              the most fiendish crime on record.
              "I Did Not Kill My Wife."
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1897-12-10/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Adolph+Luetgert+wife&st=text&r=0.679,0.225,0.343,0.386,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>LUETGERTSVIFE SEtN IN BOSTON
              Startling Declaration Made
              By a St Louis Man
              r
              GAVE HER REASONS
              FOR LEAVING HOME
              U
              It Was Because of Luetgerts
              Actions With Other Women
              Mr Schofield the Man Who Tells
              the Story Gives the dumber cf
              the Residence On tho Boston
              Street In Which Hrs Luetgert
              Stopped and She Had ITo Hesita
              tion In Acknovr1 edging Eer Iden
              tity Believes Her Still in Boston
              Boston Dec 9Th Globe says Mrs
              Luetgert the supposed victim of the
              sausage manufacturer murderer so
              called in Chicago is alive and well
              Mrs Luetgert was seen in this city
              during the month of July acknowledg
              ed her identity besides giving more or
              less explanation relative to the reasons
              which caused her to leave her husband
              who is again to be tried for his life
              Such was the startlirg declaration
              made by John Schofield of St Louis
              to a Globe man
              Mr Schofield supplemented this
              statement further with the positive assurance
              surance that Mrs Luetgert was at tha
              hcuse No 7 Bullfinch Place for a period
              iod of three or four days during the
              middle of July last He said he gained
              the assurance on the fact that Mrs
              Luetgert while in Boston acknowl
              edged tier identity with the assurance
              that she left her husband because of
              his actiors with other women as well
              as for reasons which she thought would
              helD him in his financial embarrass
              ment in business He further asserted
              that he believed Mrs Luetgert was still
              in Boston and that she would yet be
              found
              The Globe has interviewed Mrs Moss
              of No7 Bullfinch Place who says that
              the woman supposed to be Mrs Luet
              gert went by the name of Millie
              Barker One day the woman seemed
              distressed after reading an account of
              the trial of Luetgert and when ques
              tioned by Mrs Moss said
              You would be surprised if I told you
              who I am
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063615/1898-01-22/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Adolph+Luetgert+wife&st=text&r=0.035,0.562,0.183,0.206,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>When were jou married the second
              time7" Luetgert was asked bj' his counsel.
              "In" 1STS. to Louise BIcknose."
              There was not a trace of emotion In ther
              voice. of Luetgert as -ho mentioned the
              name of the woman he Is charged with
              having murdered.
              Luetgert proved to Imj a, vty laihrjmose
              witness, his fears coming frequently and in
              considerable volume whenever the name of
              his dead wife was .brought into ther case.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1898-02-10/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Adolph+Luetgert+wife&st=text&r=0.794,0.427,0.161,0.181,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>SAUSAG MAKER
              WAS CONvcnD 1 l
              Luetgert Jury Brought In a l
              Verdict of Murder 1
              1
              WITH A SENTENCE OF
              LIFE IMPRISONMENT
              Jury on the First Ballot Were
              Unanimous for Conviction i
              1
              On the Exception of the Verdict J
              Luetgert Laughed Does Not R
              gard It Seriously and Is Confident J
              cf a New Trial and Acquittal l J
              1few Spread Like Lightning 1
              Motion for New Trial E
              tered
              Chicago Feb 9Adolph L Luetgert
              was tonight convicted of the murder
              of his wife and sentenced to Imprison
              ment in the penitentiary for the term
              of his natural life
              Luetgert received the verdict with a
              laugh
              VERDICT SURPRISED HIM
              At first Luetgert refused to say any
              thing his one response to questions be
              ing I wont talk about It At length
              he yielded to inquiries enough to say
              that the verdict was a surprise to him
              I dont see how the evidence justified
              such a verdict but one thing is sure
              the supreme court will give me a new
              trial and I shall be acquitted  
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88053055/1899-07-28/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Adolph+Luetgert+wife&st=text&r=0.397,0.54,0.295,0.331,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>LEUTGERT DIES IN HIS CELL.
              Chicago Lawyer Declares the tfanaage
              Maker Confessed Wife Murder.
              Joliet, Ills., July 28.—Adolph L.
              Luetgert, the wealthy Chicago sausage
              maker, who
              in the penitentiary here for the mur
              der of his wife, was found dead in his
              cell yesterday. Doctors Werner and
              O'Malley held a post mortem examina
              tion, disclosing tho fact that Luetgert
              died from fatty degeneration of the
              heart.
              Frank Fay Pratt, a member of tho
              Chicago bar, said last night that
              Adolph Luetgert confessed in Febru
              ary, 1898, that he had killed his wife.
              "He told
              Mr. Pratt. "He started to tell me some
              of the details, but fell to cursing about
              the affair and I was unable to lead him
              back to an unfolding of the steps of
              the crime.
              serving a life sentence
              lie had killed her," said
              "I was connected with the Chris.
              Merry defense, and in my visits to my
              cliont I became acquainted with the
              sausage maker. 
              'Yes, that i
              I did kill my wife.
              I was possessed of the devil and killed
              her bee
              in love with
              other woman.' He then started to tell
              1 I
              about the vat, and said his wife
              attempted to make a dying statement
              to him when the dogs began to growl
              and be put
              that he switched off to cursing. As
              I considered the confession
              sional
              end to her. It
              then
              profes
              T respected it until death
              placed him beyond further
              a
              has
              human pursuit."
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn91068084/1899-08-04/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Adolph+Luetgert+wife&st=text&r=0.656,0.413,0.291,0.327,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn91068084/1899-08-04/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Adolph+Luetgert+wife&st=text&r=0.656,0.413,0.291,0.327,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>A week after her sudden disappear
              ance her brother asked the police to
              investigate. The police searched the
              factory. They drained a large vat
              filled with strong acid. At the bottom
              they foun,U two gold rings, one of which
              was inscribed with Mrs. Leutgert'
              Initials; some steel corset stays and
              a bone of a woman's foot. This was all
              that was ever found of tho missing
              woman.
              Leutgert made a hard fight in court.
              His first trial resulted In a disagree
              ment, but at his second trial be was
              found guilty of the murder and sen
              tenced to the penitentiary.
              </text>
      </result>



    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
