<topics>

  <topic>

    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-alaska-purchase</id>
    
    <results>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1867-04-09/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Russian+Russia+Treaty+Empire+Seward&st=text&r=-0.285,-0.078,1.569,1.569,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>The Russian Treaty
        Admiral Fox, on his return from his visit to Russia, told a friend in this city that Prince 
        a Gertsehakoff had said to him in St. Petersburg that
        the territory which Russia owned in America was not only valueless to his Government, but was
        an expense and trouble which the Czar
        would gladly be rid of, and assured him that Russia
        willing to cede the territory to the United States as a gift if it were 
        iblie.
        but was
        would be
        States as a gift if it were desirable to the Republic. 
        This is certain, It is equally certain that Secretary
        Seward kuew of the fact. Unfortunately for our
        Treasury and our tax-payers, there 18 no
        diplomatic glory to be got out of accepting a gift.
        To make a reputation out of an acquisition of terri-
        tory ready tobe handed over to us as a sheer measure
        of relict to the Russian exchequer, Mr. Seward had
        to negotiate for it, throw away $10,000,900 for it, mys-
        terionsly wrap up the transaction in a secret treaty,
        and sutidenly appear in the Senate, after the expira-
        tion of the regular session of Congress, and urge the
        jmmediate approval of the treaty on the grounds,
        rst: That the region to be acquired was relatively
        as valuable to Russia as Ireland is to England; that
        in climate and the natural wealth of timber, grain,
        lands, for-bearing animals, and fisheries, and prob-
        ably coal, and gold, and silver, it was enormonsly val-
        uable. Sceand: That if we did not immediately takeit,
        we shonld lose the opportunity, and it would become
        the property of some other nation. Third, That the
        treaty must be ratified (within 90 days or fail, and
        that. if it #ailed, every Government in Europe would
        exult over its wiscarriage, and our friendly relations
        with the powerfu) Russian Empire would be imper-
        riled by the mortification to which we had subjected
        it throughout the world. There are Senators whe
        wish that we had some form of official responsibility
        by which a Sccrelary of State could be suitably pun-
        ished for secretly and unadvisedly, and of his own
        yeckless 10lly and wastefulness, using the diplomatic
        machinery of the Government to get the conntry
        into such a fix as he is now begging the
        Senate to get it out of. There are other Senators
        who langh at the Secretary's representation of the
        necessity of proxapt action and, indeed, of any action,
        who know that the Czar does not care a button
        whether the treaty is ratified or not, and that the
        whole scheme lias been cooked up between Mr.
        RKReward and the Russian Minister, for reasons purely
        personal to each. The treaty has a clanse init bind-
        ing us to exercise jurisdiction over the territory, and
        give goveinuient to the 40,000 inhabitants that are
        now crawling over it on snow-shoes. Some of these
        are savage Indiaus of the most dangerous charaeter.
        Such on the ast murdered two boats crews under
        the command of Behring, who was himself buried on
        the strait that bears hisname. What will the gov-
        ernment of this ice-covered desert cost? Jt was
        stated at the War Department yesterday
        that it would require a regiment of infantry. It
        costs $1,100 a year to maintain a single soldier in
        Washington. It would cost twice as much in Sew-
        ard’s desert. It costs $1,000,000 a year to keep a man-
        of war at sea. We should have to have at Jeast six
        on the 3,000 miles of Seward’s coast, as naval men
        say here. We should have to institute a territorial
        government. What wouldn't that cost? Indian wars
        would inevitably follow. They could not be avoided.
        On the Nebraska plains it now costs ns $115,000 to kill
        ove Indian. It would cost $300,000 a head to kill
        Seward's Indians. There is not, in the history of di-
        plomacy, such insensate folly as this treaty; and yet
        there is a danger that the scheme to run it through
        the Senate, without publicity aud without conside-
        eration, is going to be crowned with immediate suc-
        cess. It was not under debate to-day, hut yet was
        up, in parliamentary phrase. Long documents about
        it from Mr. Seward, all rhetorical and abound-
        jog in his glittering generalities, were read at te-
        dious length. Troublesome questions were put by
        practical Senators, to which no answer could be got.
        Nobody knew anything about the country, about the
        savages, how many months in the year the larger
        part of the region was in darkness, bow human life
        could be sustained there by civilized men—nothing
        was known, but there was a deplorable impatience
        on the part of too many Senators to get to a vole, so
        @s to get to their homes. Among 100 many
        of them prevailed the idea, served up
        swallowed with the treaty roast, and the treaty
        boiled, at Mr. Seward’s dinner table, that it is fatal
        10 a public man in America to vote against an acqui-
        sition of territory. Even the motion, it issaid, which
        will be made to-morrow to remove the injunction of
        secresy, and to debate the treaty in open Senate,
        will fail. Mr. Seward has effectually cloaked both
        the debate and the vote, but he intends that the rati-
        fication of the treaty shall uncloak him apd let him
        out of the obscurity, which for two years has covered
        hiro as with the pall of death, into a glorious terri-
        torial extension splendor.
        Another dinner party to Esquimaux Senators was
        given to-night by the Secretary of State, and the
        little entertainments will be continued until the bird
        ie picked. How leng the delay in the Senate will
        render the expense of these elegant dinners neces-
        wary on the part of the hospitable Secretary is
        yet impossible to surmise. A step was taken which
        will assist in his relief to-day. Senator Romner, as
        Chairman of the Foreign Affairs Commit-
        tee, reported, as unanimously instructed by
        the Committee, in favor of ratifying the
        and
        ing at once for an extensive stumping tour throngh
        his appointment being assured as soon as the rules
        Slocum, Wood, and Ludlow, and the other hungry
        men who have heen loafing about Washington,
        and spending money all Winter, expecting
        to be appointed to the office, have found
        out, at last, that they have been most cruelly de-
        ceived by Johnson and Weed. They have almost all
        left for their homes in disgust, and chagrined attheir
        stupidity in not knowingWeed's cunning better. State
        Senator Pearson, who has been here since yesterday
        morning, accompanied by Weed, called on Postmas-
        ter-Gen. Randall to-day, and urged the appointment
        of Authony Campbell as Postmaster of Brooklyn.
        They afterward called on Seward, who, after dosing
        them with some Russian treaty statistics and in-
        viting them to one of his treaty dinners, to be given
        this evening, gave them an order for an immediate
        admission to the presence of His Excellency, Presi-
        dent Johnson. Pearson and Weed called at the
        White House with Seward’s order, but the President
        refused to see them until this evening. Pearson had
        to £o back to Albany, and was compelled to leave in
        this evening's train. Weed remains to look after
        matters. He has been waiting an audience at the
        White House most of the evening. There is a new
        candidate looming up for the Postmastership in one
        Gen. Peck. Mis stock is quoted highest to-night.
        Congressmen Robinson and Barnes are both at home,
        and rumor says that they have empowered Weed to
        act for them in the Brooklyn appointinents.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026994/1867-04-12/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Russian+Russia+Treaty+Alaska+gold+mines</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>CHARLESTON.
              FREDDY MORNING, APRIL 12, 1867.
              THE RUSSIAN TREATY.
              This treaty, annexing the Russian posses?
              sions in North America to the United States,
              has been ratified, and we have the satisfaction
              of knowing that when wc do get back into the
              Union, it will be a considerably larger Union
              than when wc left it. There appears to be
              some doubt as to the character and extent of
              the advantages of which we will then be par?
              takers. Tho most liberal statement of the i
              friends of the treaty, embrace positive coal j
              mines, possible gold mines, a sufficient supply
              of furs, a surplus of fish, and ice enough to
              make a national ice-house, and to do away
              with the necessity of a protective tariff on the
              domestic manufacture of that very important
              article.
              Mr. SEWARD'S diplomatic life has been very
              eventful, and with great difficulties he has had,
              thanks to us, great success. Although ably
              supported by Mr. ADAMS, at London, and Mr.
              DAYTON, at Paris, he has owed much to fortune
              and to General GRANT; and the Trent affair,
              after all, can only take its place iu diplomatic
              history as au ingenious extrication from a not
              very pardonable blunder. But the foreign
              minist er who has added 880,000 square miles
              to the area of the republic, has certninly some
              solid ground to stand upon, and as that terri?
              tory is said to contain the highest mountain in
              the world, he has provided a fit pinnacle from
              which the American Eagle can, when the days
              of good feeling come back, "spread itself"
              over the immense country ihai will then lie
              peacefully beneath the shadow of its wings.
              And now, as this is achieved, and especially as
              thc sixty day notes no longer need renewal, I
              but have been paid up in full with interest, the j
              venerable SIMEON, of the Slate Department, j
              can say to Mr. JOHNSON: NOW let thy servant
              depart iu the blessed hope of diplomatic im
              mortality.
              The treaty is a wise one, and the Senate did
              right to ratify it even if tho territory is not as
              valuable as represented. And the price is
              scarcely worth considering when we reflect I
              that either Mr. PEABODY, Mr. ASTOR, or Com?
              modore VANDERBILT could have paid it, or Mr.
              JEROME could have bought and divided it into
              prize farms to the successful competitors for
              "gentlemanly conduct."
              It is very clear that, following the instinct
              of proprietorship that is always developed from
              a plantation*to an empire, we intend to own
              this continent, "from the centre all round to
              the sea,'' and to realize the humorous anticipa?
              tion of one of our old-time statesmen, who,
              upon the acquisition of louisiana, exclaimed:
              "We are growing-we are growing." Just
              think what splendid mileage those fellows will
              have who are Senators from Patagonia and th?
              North Pole.
              Russia did not want the country; we would
              not have let anybody elss have it; so we made
              a fair trade, and now, while French and Eng?
              lish, Austrians and Prussians, Russians and
              Italians, are quarreling over Eastern questions
              ?nd German questions, Brother Jonathan can
              sit with sublime indifference on the top of thc
              Alleghenies and spit his tobacco into either the
              Atlantic or Pacific, whitling huge California
              Limber with a clasp knife made of iron ont of
              Iiis mountains, and mix; his cobbler with
              lemons grown in his own tropics, and cooled
              ?viih ice brought from his own Arctic circle..
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82015486/1867-04-18/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Value+Acquisition+Russia+Russian+Treaty+Treaty+Seward&r=0.021,0.078,0.387,0.218,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        The purchase of the Russian American
        possessions is severely condemned by
        large portion of onr people. It is claim
        flct that we have merely secured. large
        extent of bleak territory, ntterly worth
        less for any practical nee. We have no
        doubt tbe same was s2id of Jefferson's
        Louisiana purchase, yet time baa shown
        the territory thus acquired to he; among
        ,fke most valuable and -important of all
        tbe United States possessions. So it
        will prove, we faave.no doubt, with the
        Russian purchase.
        The United States had withQ her lim
        its men of almost every knewn race and
        .nationality. But of the graceful, band
        t-iome, energetic, intellectual and dainty
        Esquimaux, we do not believe she had a
        single one. By tbe purchase of Bussian
        America, she at once acquires a vast
        aumber of these highly useful and orna
        mental citizens, who, in the progress of
        the great principles of the Declaration of
        Independence and Impartial Suffrage,
        rill aoon become intelligent and inde
        pendent voters, and will be studiously
        conrted by ambitions politicians.
        be possession of health and vigor is
        essential to the permanency and power
        of a nation. v Health and vigor depend
        principally upon iooa ana naoits. uar
        new brethren, the Esquimaux, are among
        the stoutest and hardiest people known
        They subsist chiefly upon the flesh of the
        Walrus, which doubtless imparts this
        rigor. The United States bad not
        walrns in all her broad domain. By tbe
        purchase of Bussian America, she secures
        aa abundance of walruses. Who doubts
        that the result will be a speedy increase
        oT.atrengtb' and vigor in our people, and
        increased power to make other acquisi
        tions, whereby we may produce other ar
        tides which now have to be imported
        from foreign countries
        t has been the boast of the United
        States, that she. possessed almost every
        variety of climate. This was an empty
        boast she had no frigid zone. But she
        can now make the boast truthfully for
        in the purchase of Bussian America, she
        has acquired a vast extent of frigid zone,
        aad soon icebergs will become an article
        of United States production.
        These are but a few of the many ad
        vantages secured by our new acquisition
        and all for tbe paltry sum of seven
        millions of dollars. Yet there are those
        who'objeci to it, and grumble at it
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85034039/1867-05-03/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Russia+Russian+Treaty+Gold+Seward&r=0.399,0.378,0.548,0.308,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Tho Russian Treaty has been mado
        public, apparently without authority,
        and is printed in our columns to-day.
        In tho first article tho boundaries of the
        ceded territory aro defined in tho sec
        ond is trunsftrrod to tho United States
        tho titlo of all public property with tho
        exception of tho Greek Churches, which
        aro to remain tho property of their mem
        bers in tho third, it is stipulated that
        tho inhabitants, excepting uncivilized
        tribes, shall, after three yoars residence,
        be admitted to citizonship of tho United
        States, while tho Esquimaux and Indi
        ans shall bo subject to our authority
        in tho fourth, tho formal terms of cx
        chango aro definod the fifth provides
        for tho withdrawal of Russian troops
        in tho sixth, tho cession of territory and
        dominion is declared to bo frco and un
        incumbered by an reservations and in
        tho seventh, tho date of ratification is
        fixod.
        It is at least a satisfaction to know
        that the treaty binds our Government to
        no moro than a payment of a certain
        sum in gold, and tho admission of Rus
        sian settlors to citizenship, and that any
        slight valuo tho cession may have is not
        lessoned by reservations in favor of
        British hunters and traders. To share
        tho questionable advantages of tho ter
        ritorv would bo to yield tbem entirely
        for there are somo things which oro too
        small to bo divided. But though tbis is
        theoretically a satisfaction, practically
        it would havo mado no approciablo dif
        tcrence to the people ot this country
        an tho traders in xsortu America hac
        been given equal rights in the territory
        by tho treaty. In tho deserts of Russian
        America tho laws aro not likely to bo
        enforced, and tho hunters nround tho
        Great Beard Lake will care littlo for the
        141st degree of wost latitude Wo sim
        ply obtain by tho troaty tho nominal pos-
        sofSion of impassable deserts of snow,
        vast tracts of dwarf tunbor, frozen riv
        ers, inaccessible mountain ranges, with
        a few islands whero tho climato is moro
        moderate and a scanty population is
        supported by fishing nnd trading with
        the Indians. Virtually wo get, by an
        expenditure of seven millions in gold,
        Sitka and tho.Pnnco ot Wales Islands.
        All tho rest is wasto territory, and no
        energy of tho American people will bo
        sufficient to make mining speculations
        in tho sixtieth degreo north latitude
        profitablo, or to reclaim wildernesses
        which border on tho Arctic Ocean. A
        glance at tho map will Bhow that this
        .L-
        mignty anjuiBiuoii, nun mo uiuojiuuu
        of a few islands scattered olong a moun
        tainous and sterile shoro, lies above tho
        sixtieth degree, nnd is divided into noar-
        IV equal pnnioiie y iuu niuuu lihiu.
        Nitictv-nino hundredths of Russian
        America are absolutely useless the re
        mainine hundredth may be of somo val
        uo to tho Russians who Bettlod it, but is
        certainly not worth Beven millions of
        dollars to a nation already possessed of
        moro territory than it can decently gov
        ern, and burdened with debt. On tho
        ontrory. it is certain that the expenso
        and trouble of a Territorial government
        or six governments, as wo hear air.
        Howard proposes in this distant and
        inhosnifablo land.' would far outweigh
        1. s
        any advontago from its codfish or boar-
        skins. To Russia it was an embarrass
        ment, and by the next session of Con
        gress we trust tho folly of tho purchase
        will be made bo plain that tno iiouse
        will refuse to make the necessary appro
        priation. New York Tribuno.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86053571/1867-12-24/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Alaska+Russia+Russian+Treaty+Seward+Sitka&st=text&r=0.024,0.117,0.194,0.252,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Aa our readeri know, we hare favored the
        treat wblch convey to the United States these
        rro infra formerly belonging to Russia) end we
        think that we cannot do our reader! end the
        public generally a better aerriee than to lay be
        fore them la our eolamna tome of the facta and
        Incident! atated by thla writer, which go to ihow
        the geography, the condition of the people, and
        the rcaourcea of that far-off land.
        Of the extent of thla Territory tnlteorreopond
        ent etyat
        "It Ilea between the 130th and the UOthdrgreet
        of western longitude, and lying with the ahorea
        of the i roien oeean on the north and the Paclfl
        on the touth, la that broad area of territory newly
        acquired by the American Republic, now desig
        nated by the name of Alaska. It la by far the
        moat northern portion of our national domain.
        Its area In square mllea la not definitely known.
        Moat of the reocraphles put It et.no.000. Mr.
        Sumner thlnka tt la about 6T0.0OO. He la mora
        nearly correct, thouih U maybe 20,0(10 more, or
        perhaps 20,000 less NO American map, aa yet.
        irhes a correct Idea of Ita toDOfi-ranhv,
        arc rlrers aa large ea the Hudson ana Susque-
        iorr
        nnam, nnu iiiduoi rrrnicrarca muminuis
        of Ithode Island, w hlcn hare no name or locality
        on our achool-roora maps."
        "Between East port (Maine) and Uape Flat
        tery, our previous longitudinal extremes, the
        distance Is 67 degreea a difference In time of 3
        lioun and M minutes But the "transfer" of
        three weiiii ago rives the United States a reach
        from the eastern boundary of Maine, In the 57th
        iicgrr oi lougiiuur, io in isiana oi Altoo, 10
        longitude 1S ehowlnjr a difference of time be
        tween the two limits of S hours and I minutes.
        hen to-day at noon the robuat Aroostook
        farmer sits down to hta Yankee repeat of baked
        beans and pork, the moat western Inhabitants
        of the American Hepublle will be burled In sleep
        on the leach of a little harbor of the Island of
        Attoo the tlsh still awlmmlng In the bay which
        (lie hours later are to furnish them a breakfast.
        I hey are as yet unconscious of the fact that they
        are included among the Universal Yankee Na
        tion." 
        The population of Sitka Is not large. The
        Russian population la about W4 the Creoles,
        (half-breeds,) SMi the Indians about 1,000. The
        town haa been built about slaty years, and owes
        Its origin to the sea otter, the moat valuable of
        fur-bearing animals
        The town at present la not of much account as
        a place of residence, or as a mart of trade and
        business except so far as It Is used as a fur depot.
        Sitka appears to be the general storing place for
        all the furs sent In from some twenty-nine differ
        ent outposts. The amount oi tun now In store
        there amount to 360,000. We quote further
        from this correspondent as fellows. It would
        !T thai the-miarlms of Yftukee land are al
        ready there t
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025293/1868-07-24/ed-1/?sp=6&q=Boundless+Alaska+Russia+Russian+Treaty+Seward&st=text&r=0.063,0.539,0.606,0.606,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        THIS WHOLE BOUNDLESS
        The House has voted the appropriation
        of $7,200,000 for Alaska, and it is now
        past doubt a Territory of the United
        States. The exchange of treaties took
        place June 20O, 1867, and the money was
        to have been paid April 20, 1868, our
        military forces having, in the meantime,
        taken possession. It was feared that
        the failure of the House might lead to
        unpleasant complications with Russia,
        but that power which has manifested
        toward the United States, these many
        years,'a friendly spirit, duly reciprocated,
        has not urged us. Mr. Butler endeavor
        ed to put a rider on the resolution with
        holding some half million dollars claim
        ed to be due, we believe, a Massachusects
        firm for munitions of war manufactured
        for Russia during the Crimean war, but
        the House rejected it. WVith the many,
        we believe the purchase of Alaska was
        inopportune, and yet accord that in many
        respects it is valuable to the United
        states. It loosens the hold of one great
        alien power from this continent it place.
        British Columbia in a position that ren'%
        ders its annexation to the United States
        desirable, perhaps essential to its wel
        fare. We are absorbing the continent
        that is America's destiny. It gives us
        170,000 square miles of territory-larger
        than England, Ireland, Scotland, Wales,
        D~enmiark, Sweeden and Norway com
        bined. It gives us four thousand miles
        of sea coast; wi.th fine harbors and a coast
        line of 11,000: with fisheries ten times
        larger than those of the Atlantic. They
        last year sent twenty cargoes of fish, 22,
        :3663,000 pounds, into San Francisco. Mr.
        Johnson, of Californiw, stated in the
        Hlouse, they wouUld thufs year send ten
        times that amount, and in three years,
        with American enterprise, supply the
        markets of the world. It gives us great
        forests of ship timber, and the trade
        winds of the Pacific six months in the
        year brings the commerce of Asia along
        its shores, another additional argument
        for the Northern Pacific Railroad, by
        which it would'save the distance tmom
        Puget Souad to San Francisco. Alaska
        may appear valueless now. It is only.
        a few years since the half continent west
        of the Missouri was so esteemed. It is
        conuidered valuable now. Alaska may
        net prove to have been a bad purchase,
        evvt though it was untimely. The gov.
        erumest had punrchased it. 
        It had agrred to pay for it. 
        It hs done so. It is well.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86053571/1868-07-15/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Alaska&st=text&r=0.038,0.995,0.185,0.241,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Alaska. The bill appropriating the pur
        rinse money for Alaska was passed the House
        of Ileprcsentatlvcf, yesterday, by a dcUslve
        ote yeas, 101 J nays, 3 This Is right. Ucn
        rl Hanks has done nobly In this cauat, and
        rough hit energy and perseverance It haa
        !icu carried. He waa warmly congratulated
        y hit frleoda on the triumph of thla met sure.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85054468/1899-07-15/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Golden+Alaska+Alliance+Cape+Nome+Gold&st=text&r=0.264,0.757,0.266,0.347,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Glowing DcHcriiitlonH of the "Wealth
        of the Cape .Nome Iletrlon.
        Seattle, Wash., July 14. The steel steam
        ship Alliance, Captain Hardwlck, arrived
        from St. Michaels early this. morning, the
        first vessel to arrive from that ice-bound
        port. The Alliance brought but $15,000 in
        gold. Her passengers bad drafts for a
        much larger amount but the big gold ship
        ments will follow on regular express
        steamers. She was followed Into port by
        the steamer Otizaba, from Skaguay, with
        $100,000 In dust in possession of twenty
        miners. The Alliance had the first news
        that has been received from the newly dis
        covered gold region around Cape Nome
        since last February. There were bcvcral
        Cape Nome miners on the Alliance. All
        brought out more or less gold.
        The story they tell Is wonderful. J. W.
        Price brought $10,000 worth of Capo Nome
        gold to St. Michaels. It represented eight
        days' work two feet below the surface on
        claim 8 "on Glacier Creek. L Loenberg, a
        German soldier, has a claim on Dexter
        Creek, that Is producing an ounce per hour.
        If .he had sluice boxes he could clean up
        $1,000 per day without difficulty. Gold
        seems to pay from the grass roots down.
        Three men on Snow Gulch, a new discov
        ery, cleaned up $4,000 In four days Dr.
        Kettleson, the Government reindeer agent,
        has a claim on the same gulch that has
        never jielded less than $15 to the ran, and
        averages $30. Deer Creel: 13 fabuloutly
        rich. As much as $20,000 is offered for
        unproapected claims. Owners on Ophlr
        Creek are holding for $150,000 for each
        claim. David S. Lane, cf San Francisco,
        is the only actual miner out from the new
        gold fields. He says that the poor miner
        has not much chance, as all the rich
        claims are staked.
        The commandant of Fort St. Michaels
        Intends sending Federal troops to Nome
        City shortly. There will be considerable
        trouble over claims located by poner cf
        attorney. There had been several shooting
        affrays already and serious r!ot3 are an
        ticipated when the big crowd that stam
        peded from Dawson arrives. Scurvy and
        frost created great havoc among the miners
        who stampeded to Cape Nome In Dccem
        bar last. Seven of a party Trom Iloljoke.
        Mass., died of scurvy and several Call
        fornlans wire frozen to death on the trail.
        The scurvy camp of the Holyo'.te party
        was a terrible sight when found by well
        miners fiom Gulovln Bay. The following
        from Holvoko wero dead. Dr Brlgham
        K. Rodney, G. Groticau, Joe Fountain, and
        three other French Canadians.
        
        
        
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024828/1899-09-30/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Alaska+Alaskan+Field+Treasure+Cape+Nome+Gold&r=-0.114,0.574,0.896,0.583,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045366/1903-09-12/ed-1/?sp=11&q=Alaska+Alaskan+Russia+Gold+Cape+Nome+Seward+Present&st=text&r=0.031,0.817,0.249,0.323,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        When Secretary Seward purchased
        Alaska from Russia in 1867 for $7,200,000
        the anti-expansionists of that period ridi
        culed the transaction as a piece of su
        preme folly and the public generally
        agreed that he had bought nothing in par
        ticular except a few fur seals and a vast
        expanse of Icebergs and glaciers.
        The commerce of Alaska for the year
        ending June 30, 1903, amounted to over
        $21,000,000, not including the gold out
        put, which would add nearly $5,000,000
        more.' It is officially stated that since
        Alaska became American territory it has
        exported furs, fish and gold in about equal
        values to the amount of $150,000,000, while
        investments of American capital In Alaska
        have reached $25,000,000. To this should
        be added considerable sums employed in
        furnishing transportation to Alaska The
        same official authority estimates the ag
        gregate shipments of merchandise to
        Alaska from the United States during the
        same period at $100,000,000. It takes
        something more than, a few seals and ice
        bergs to develop a c6mmerce of such di
        mensions. That this is "only the small
        beginning of what is to follow in the not
        far distant future is my firm belief.
        do not wish to be misunderstood.
        Alaska at the present time does not offer
        the opportunities to poor men which
        should attract them in large numbers.
        There are no "diggings" like the bea,ch
        sands at Nome, where men with only a
        shovel and a pan can wash out a mod
        erate fortune in a few days. Such re
        markably rich deposits of gbld may be
        found again, capable of being worked in
        the same primitive and inexpensive way,
        winter when matters of legisla
        tion affecting Alaska were under,
        consideration by the senate commit
        tee on territories the members 6f that
        committee felt considerably embarrassed
        by their lack of accurate and reliable in
        formation as to the real needs of that
        district. No member of the committee
        had ever Been Alaska. Advice was prof
        fered on various subjects from various
        sources, not all of which, the. committee
        felt, could be relied upon as valuable or
        disinterested. The conclusion could not
        be evaded that the proper thing for the
        committee to do was to send a delegation
        of its own members to Alaska during the
        summer vacation to study the district
        politically and commercially and from
        every other standpoint. Senator Bever
        ldge, chairman of the committee, selected
        as such subcommittee Senator W. P. Dil
        lingham of "Vermont, ohairman of the sub
        committee Senator H. E. Burnham of
        New Hampshire, Senator Knute Nelson
        of Minnesota, and Senator Thomas W.
        Patterson of Colorado, the latter as the
        representative of the democratic minor
        ity I was fortunate enough to secure,
        thru the kindness of Senator Beveridge,
        permission to accompany this senatorial
        subcommittee on their tour of investiga
        tion The party was in the charge of
        Colonel D M. Ransdall, sergeant-at-arms
        of the United States senate. Other mem
        bers of the party were Secretaries A. C.
        Johnson of Denver and J, F. Hayes of
        Indianapolis I was extremely fortunate,
        too. In having for my traveling com
        panion as far as Dawson, George A.
        Brackett, who is so well known and so
        highly esteemed at home In Minneapolis,
        and whose name, I find, is held in equally
        high regard thruout Alaska. He was re
        turning to look after Important mining
        interests of his own in Atlin, on the
        Canadian side.
        
        </text>
      </result>

      <!-- Additional queries -->

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88086023/1909-02-10/ed-1/?sp=5&q=Seward%27s+Folly&r=-0.012,-0.117,1.258,0.818,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86053571/1869-05-11/ed-1/?sp=2&q=alaska+treaty&r=0.075,-0.023,0.605,0.34,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Onr way of doing' things Is a punle to tho
              members of the legation. They s,ee ns bay
              AtaskarwhlcVntibody wants, and ratify the
              treaty with the dtesentlhjf -rotet only M Mr.
              Fessenden and Mrv Ferry. ThM they see ns
              bny Bt. Thomas, which a good many persons
              bellevo to bo a valuable acquisition, and
              neglect to act upon the treaty for more than
              two years. Tbey see the Senate ratify tho
              Alaska treaty all but unanimously, and then
              see the noose in a snarp ana tong couiesico
              struggle over tho question of appropriating
              the money to carry It into effect. They
              learn that the Alaska treaty was carried on
              the argument that It would be a breach of
              good faith to reject It, and then find a largo
              part of the Senato and a considerable pro
              portion of our people deaf to this argument
              when used In connection with tne St.
              Thomas treaty. 1 happen to know that there
              has been a deal of this sort of talk in the
              l.imttAn lli rut at wlntirt nnil An ft til
              members pat the points with much force in a
              long conversation only three' or four days
              ago. "Now tell me." be sold la coocltsioa,
              "who anions these Americans has the trentr
              Umn the House-either one, either two
              making power! It It the President or the
              rtr all Lhraal"
              Ono of the gentlemen near the mlnltUr
              putt It In something like this wayi "We gave
              yoa all yon asked i we conceded all that Mr.
              Adams ever claimed t we flnallr stirnod a
              treaty entirely satisfactory to your Mr. John
              son and your Mr. Seward, your Secretary of
              8tate from the beginning of tho war, and
              your minister to whom the Senators all
              agreed) we do that, and then yoa tarn round
              and kick the treaty out of doors. Pray tell
              me what are we to do!" I am merely say
              ing how these Engtlsh diplomats do look at
              It. If I understand them, they are a little
              confused by our way of doing things they
              seem reasonably willing to consider oor case.
              but say they cannot clearly teo what onr
              case is ana uy wnom u n rerrcacnicu.
              </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020274/1904-04-18/ed-1/?sp=6&q=purchase+of+alaska&r=-0.144%2C0.854%2C0.877%2C0.57%2C0&st=text</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        VALUE OF ALASKA.
        It is generally conceded that the purchase of
        Alaska was a friendly payment to Russia 'for hav
        ing sent fleets of war vessels to the harbors of San
        Francisco and New York during tho Civil War; and
        it Is generally believed that the purchase would not
        have been made had the offer been tendered by any
        nation other than Russia. James G. Blaine, In his
        "Twenty Years in Congress," devotes considerable
        space to the purchase of Alaska and shows that Rus
        sia was much more anxious to sell 'than we were
        to buy.
        Alaska was considered a region of ice and' rock,
        of no value whatever from either a commercial or a
        strategic point of view. Its purchase caused a vio
        lent discussion in Congress, but the wisdom of the
        act Is now seen. Alaska was purchased In 1808 for
        $7,000,000 and It has produced, according to recent
        statistics, $150,000,000 in gold, fish and furs, and has
        bought from the United States merchandise to the
        value of $100,000,000. In 1003 it sold fish to the
        value of $8,000,000 and bought' merchandise to the
        value of $10,228,004 from the United States.
        Those who are familiar with the Territory say
        that all its resources are not yet known. This state
        ment Is borne out by the recent- dispatches stating
        that coal has been discovered and, what is more Im
        portant, that the coal Is commercial fuel. One re
        port states that it is practically Inexhaustible. Sev
        eral new gold fields are being opened. It Is claimed
        that there is no appreciable decrease in the fish out
        put of the Aluikan waters.
        It Is thus seen that Alaska has become one of our
        most valuable dependencies and that Its value to the
        United States increases year by year. There Is no
        parly which can claim the honor of its purchase or
        seek to countenance the purchase of other territories
        by pointing to Alaska as an example of value of a
        territory. Its purchase was an accident of di
        plomacy.
        
        
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88064250/1899-08-19/ed-1/?sp=1&q=purchase+of+alaska&r=0.007%2C0.003%2C1.164%2C0.654%2C0&st=text</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        WHEN Secretary Seward pro
        posed to purchase Alaska he
        was met by' a storm of ridi
        cule not only in this country, but from
        all portions of the world. Diplomats,
        politicians and the common people felt
        that it would be as wise to bury a trifle
        over $7,000,000 at the north pole as to
        use it for. the purchase of Alaska. The
        great expanse of territory belonging
        to Russia in North America was looked
        upon as a land of icebergs and snow,
        of frozen rivers and unprofitable moun
        tain peaks, out of 'which it would be
        impossible to secure any adequate re
        turns for the money invested in its pur
        chase, to say nothing of its mainte
        nance.
        But Secretary Seward thought differ
        ently. He realized that this frozen
        northland presented great possibilities.
        It is doubtful if he considered the pos
        sibility of the territory becoming a fac
        tor in the production of the world's
        gold, but he did see the advantages It
        offered to our fishing, whale and seal
        industries, and in these alone Alaska
        has fully verified the expectations of
        the secretary.
        So great was Seward's desire to ac
        quire the territory of Russian America
        that when the Russian minister at
        Washington announced to him the
        willingness of the Russian emperor to
        sell, he lost no time in.completing his
        part of the negotiations. On the even
        ing of March 29, 1867, Secretary Sew
        ard was playing whist at his Home in
        Washington when the Russian minis
        ter called and announced that 'he had
        AL. igjJ SJ4ND, ALASKA.
        received the necessary permission to
        sign a treaty ceding the territory to the
        United States. Seward would not wait
        until morning to sign the treaty, but,
        cummoning the necessary clerks of the
        state department, he requested the
        minister to meet him at the depart
        ment building. There, early the next
        morning, between four and five o'clock,
        the signatures of the two statesmen
        were placed to the paper that trans
        ferred Alaska from Russia to the United
        States. The treaty was sent to the
        senate at once, where .t was finally rati
        fied, amid the jeers of the world.
        By this purchase of Alaska for $7,
        200,000 the United States added a terri
        tory equaling in area one-seventh of
        the territory of the United States. It
        placed San Francisco east of the center
        of American possessions, and made
        possible the claim that the "sun never
        sets on Old Glory." San Francisco lies
        2,900 miles west of Maine, and Attu
        island, the western extremity of
        Alaska, lies 2,943 miles west of San
        Francisco. When the summer sun is
        4.i, I
        HON. W/ WRD
        HON. W. H. SEWARD.
        setting at Attu island day is breaking
        over the Maine forests.
        But Alaska has proven the truth of
        Secretary Seward's predictions, and
        has to-day paid for itself many times
        over. And yet the wonderful resources
        of this land of snow and ice are but be
        ginning to be developed. One of the
        things that Secretary Seward saw in
        Alaska was its furs. Up to the pres
        ent time the fur companies have taken
        from the territory a little over $33,000,
        000 worth of seal skins, and hate paid
        into the treasury of the United States
        over $6,000.000 in royalties. The seal
        are rapidly dying off, but it will still
        be many years before the industry in
        Alaska is entirely dead, and the gov
        ernment will receive many more mil
        lions from this source. From this
        source of revenue there is still $1,340,
        533 in dispute, a large part of which
        the government will receive in time.
        Royalties on furs have more than paid
        the purchase price of Alaska.
        The annual value of the whale fish
        eries of Alaska has to be estimated, but
        competent judges place it at not less
        than $2,000,000 at the present time, and
        estimate the total. since the cession of
        the territory at more than $20,000,000.
        None of this basgone directly into the
        government treasury, but it has all
        gone to enrich the American people.
        Alaskan fisheries, exclusive of whales
        and seals, are estimated to have turned
        out a product valued at more than $68,.
        000,000 since the territory was ceded
        to us. Of this amount that of salmon
        fisheries bhave exceeded $30,000,000,
        and are to-day yielding close to $4,000,
        000 a year, all of which is going into
        American pockets.
        What the mineral resoursas of Alaska
        are cannot even be estimated with any
        degree of accuracy.. Every vessel re
        turning from the Yukon district is
        bringing into the western ports thou
        sands of dollars worth of the yellow
        metal. In 1897 more than $15,000,000
        worth of gold was taken out. of the
        territory, and again last year half of
        this amount was dug out of those
        mountains and frozen streams which
        a New York congressman would have
        had the president pay $7,200,000 to some
        European power to take off our hands.
        Unlike Secretary Seward, that gentle
        man could see nothing of value in the
        great territory which Russia sold to
        us for a mere song.
        Since the opening of the Treadwell
        mine, one of the largest and most valu
        able gold mines of the world, it has
        paid in dividends to its stockholders
        close to $7,000,000, and its owners are
        digging out of Alaska $2,500,000 a year,
        which in itself would pay a good rate
        of interest on the purchase price of
        the entire territory.
        What the next ten years will see in
        Alaska is hard to estimate, but that
        the territory gives promise of becom
        ing of much greater importance than
        it is to-day none will deny. Aside
        from the resources which are no.
        showing such wonderful developments,
        there are others which have as yet
        hardly been touched. Its agriculture
        and its timber offer opportunities for
        riches that will in time be the won
        der of the world.
        While we think of It as a land of cold
        and ice, yet the winters in parts of the
        territory are milder than those of the
        northern states. While it is not an
        ideal agricultural district, yet parts of
        it offer as many advantages for agri
        culture as are found in northern Scot
        land or Norway, and recent experi
        ments of the agricultural department
        have demonstrated that it is not the
        great cold, barren wilderness that it
        is supposed to be. Even as far north as
        Circle City, Dawson and the towns
        along the Yukon river men have found
        it profitable to engage in agricultural
        pursuits.
        Alaska has entered Yp' i 'an era of
        prosperity. Like the growth of our
        western towns, it started with a boom
        from which there was a certain amount
        of recoil, but the prosperity is there
        to stay, and in time this land that was
        so heartily despised only 30 years ago,
        will be one of the valuable portions of
        American territory.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025121/1893-02-07/ed-1/?sp=11&q=purchase+of+alaska&r=0.041%2C0.481%2C0.868%2C0.564%2C0&st=text</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        There have been but two exceptions
        to this policy that the writer
        can think of, those of the acquirement
        01 tue nortnern portion of .Mexico
        after the Mexican war and the purchase
        of Alaska. The former was
        simpiy tne natural spoils of war, a
        country already largely peopled with
        American citizens and controlled by
        American interests, the Bio Grande
        river was the natural boundary line
        between the two nations and no other
        course but to absorb the territory now
        comprised in Texas, Arizona and Xew
        Mexico seems to have been open.
        With the acquisition of- Alaska
        underentirely different circumstances
        the of the United States
        made its first departure in the shape
        of acquiring foreign territory by other
        means than by war. There are many
        probably in this city, who, like my-
        seu, remeniDer tne nowi or indignation
        that went over the United States
        when General Grant's Cabinet made
        public the purchase of Alaska from
        .Russia for the paltry s am of six million
        dollars. The purchase was denounced
        by the press and people as
        being contrary to the avowed policy
        of the government as well as being
        worthless, etc. We now realize that
        the purchase of Alaska was an act of
        foresight and wisdom, and that it bids
        fair to become one of the brightest
        and wealthiest of the American
        If the United States finallv decide
        to accept this proposition Hawaii will
        soon become one of the happiest and
        most prosperous people on tne globe.
        If not, there is but one thing left to do.
        Hawaii has placed itself on record
        as desiring the highest form of republican
        government, and if the United
        States will not have her, she must
        take care of herself, and establish a
        republic of her own, under a joint protectorate
        as at pwsent.
        In any event she is committed to
        a republican form of government.
        Hoping I have not trespassed too
        much on your valuable space, and
        with best wishes for the success of the
        new Government. Very respectfully,
        Tourist.
        
        </text>
      </result>

    </results>

  </topic>

  <topic>

    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-christmas-carols/selected-articles</id>

    <results>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1904-12-25/ed-1/?dl=page&q=christmas+carol&sp=12&st=text&r=-0.286,-0.079,1.571,1.571,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        AN ANCIENT CHRISTMAS CUSTOM AND THE CAROL WHICH ACCOMPANIED IT AND IS PROBABLY THE OLDEST CAROL EXTANT.
        Reproduced from H. E. ELrehbleTs "Christmas Carols and Customs" in the holiday book number of "The Outlook." by courtesy of the publishers.
        Slow and tnajestic. Adapted from an arrangement by i£. F. Rimbacit.
        BRINGING IN THE BOAE'S HEAD.
        THE BO AITS HEAD FEAST.
        Celebration of It Kept Up for
        Many Centuries.
        Then was brought fn the lusty brawn
        By blue-coated serving-man;
        Then the grim boar's bead frowned on high.
        Crested with bays and rosemary.
        Well can the green-garbed ranger tell
        How, when and whrre the monster fell;
        What dogs before his death he tore
        And all the baiting of the boar.
        To-day (or probably to-morrow if the official
        i 'hristmas festivities are postponed till then
        out of deference to Sunday) Queen's College,
        Oxford, will be the scene of "a right merrie
        jousto of ye olden tyme.," which will illustrate
        as well as any ceremony can how fondly the
        human heart and imagination cling to pretty
        mummeries ages after their origin and signifi
        cance have been forgotten. There will be a
        notable gathering in the hall of the college, and
        i notable feast in which not only the college
        iries and students will participate, but
        t chosen circle of friends and strangers
        who have been lucky enough to secure invita
        tions. There will be a banquet and merry
        n king and sinking-, and at a supreme moment,
        for which the feasters will have been waiting
        with the pegs of curiosity and emotion set high
        and tense, there will be enacted a spectai le
        which for 5C4 years has warmed the hearts and
        delighted the eyes of the d< nizens of the ven
        erable college. First will come a procession of
        the provost and fellows in all the glory of their
        regalia. Then from without will be heard the
        warning call of a trumpet, and following tho
        procession will come three bearers bringing in
        the historical boar's head. A monster head it
        will be if such can be obtained, one weighing
        sixty or seventy pounds, ".surmounted by a
        crown, wreathed with gilded sprays of laurel and
        b: mistletoe and rosemary, with small ban
        ners surrounding." With the bearers will come
        the college precentor, who will announce his
        presence and purpose by singing a carol, which
        may be in one of its several forms as old as the
        ceremony, though it must be thousands
        ol years younger than the precursors of the
        function which it enlivens. After each stanza
        the whole company will join lustily in the Latin
        refrain:
        Caput aprl def< ro,
        Reddens laudes Domino.
        Alter ;he feast the ornaments which had
        de ked the boar's head will be distributed among
        ited guests.
        The melody of the "Boar's Head Carol" is that
        d above, but there are several versions of
        the words. At the present linn- the folia
        version is used:
        h< loa r's head in hand be r I.
        ck< And 1 pray you, my r>
        lot >mi in convivio
        ■k. i
        i nr r 'i> fero.
        [ie4d< i lav. es Dumln
        Th. boar's he <1 as I und< r.-t
        J.s the bravest d sh In all the
        NEW-YORK TRIBUNE ILLUSTRATED SIITLEMKNT.
        When thus bedecked with a gay garland
        Let us servire cantico.
        Onr steward hath provided this
        In honor of the Kins of Bliss;
        Which on this day to be served is
        In Kegiiuensi atria
        In 1521, when Wynkyn de Worde had his
        printing house "in ye flete strete. at ye syne
        of ye Sonne," he published the first of the
        printed versions, and gave it this form:
        The bore's heed in hand brynge I,
        With garlans gay and rosemary:
        And I pray you all Bynge merely,
        Ciui estis in convivio.
        The bore's heed, l understand*.
        Is the chefe service In tins lande;
        Loke wherever it be f:mde,
        Servite cum cantico.
        lie glade, lordes, both more find lasse,
        For rhis hath ordc yned our stewarde,
        ■|".i -here \'iii ;iii this Christmasse,
        Tin bore hi d w ith mustai de.
        There are two obviously older versions In
        manuscript collections; this from Balliol MSS.
        No. i
        Tho boris hed in honde I brynpe,
        With garlande -m> and byrde syngynge,
        I pray you all me to synge,
        Q d estis iri com ivio.
        (Refrain.)
        Caput aprl defero,
        Reddi L.i id< I '"Vino.
        The ;>oris h r I understand.
        Ys chiefly sirved in this londe,
        Whei so ever it may be foiioY-.
        i leraiter cum Binapio.
        Tlie boris hed, T dare well say,
        Anor; after I he vtii day
        He taketh hys 'eve and goth away,
        Kxiuit ue pati la.
        More ancient than even this seems to be that
        found in a fifteenth century collection known as
        the Porkington MSS., whi» h b* gins as follows:
        (by. hey. liey. hey, the borrys hede is axmy'd gaye;
        The borrys hede in bond 1 brynge,
        The hede ye furst nu s.
        The borris h( de. :is I yew Bay,
        He takes ins I. and grot he his way,
        Gone after the xij twel fit daj
        With h.y.
        The reference to th< departure of the boar's
        head in the last stanzas of the last two versions
        ro.s plainly to the custom of continuing the
        Christmas revels till Twelfth Night. Now,
        when, c came the custom which Queen's College
        has kept alive? Her sons treasure a legend
        that is almost, if not quite, as old as the founda
        tion, which is amusing if indefensible. Accord-
        Ing to this legend, some time about K!7t; a stu
        dem of Queen" was r< Lding his Aristotle in
        Rhotover Forest, four miles from Oxford. Sud
        denly there rushed upon him a wild boar. Taken
        by surprise, and having no other weapon, he
        closed with the furious beast and thrust the
        book down Its throat, exclaiming as he did so,
        ■its Greek!' ("Gratum est!"). What with
        this rrifying formula and th< torn clogging
        ■a th< boar j:■ his life ithoul more
        ;i I feast at Chri tmas was
        l to i. b« :i to c memorate
        this L'\«i.;. Thr. f:i.nilies ti... have matricu
        have a boar's
        hl atl ::s a cri-st and of i I h in, the Gor
        r of the family
        slew a hoar in Iluntly Wood in setf-defence
        A. D. IVXi. If that was the origin of the ius
        tom the function certaintly came a long while
        after tin- fact. There may have been a local
        cause which preserved the ceremony so strangely
        at Queen's, bat there can scarcely be a question
        but thai we nave here, as we have in the cus
        tom which used to prevail of serving a boar's
        head at family dinners in the Christmastide,
        des< ribed by Sir Walter Scoti in the lines intro
        jducing this article, a survival of a solemnity of
        much vaster antiquity than the local legends.
        The boar's head feast and celebration came
        down to us like Christmas Day itself and all its
        amiable associations— the houses decked with
        yew and mistletoe and holly, the merrymaking
        and the giftgiving from the Yule festival of our
        ancient ancestors. In Sw< den at the time of the
        winter solstice bread and cakes are baked in the
        form of a boar. Says Sandys in his book of
        Christmas carols: "Among the most celebrated
        of the festival.-; of the ancients was that In honor
        of the return of the sun, which at the winter
        solstice begins gradually to regain power and
        to as, i nd, apparently, in the horizon. Previ
        ously to this the year was drawing to a close,
        and the world was typically considered to be In
        the same state. The promised restoration tl f
        light arid commencement of a new era were
        therefore hailed with rejoicings and thanksgiv
        ings." An.] Shrimpton in his "Oxford." discuss
        big the boar's head ceremonial, says:
        Undoubtedly the custom takes its rise from an
        ancient Babylonish Sun Festival, during which
        a wild boar was sacrificed to Adonis, or Tam
        muz. the Sun God, because A lonis (also known
        as Nimrod) was said to have been kill. .1 by the
        tusk of a boar, a boar's head being always
        served up at the festival. Egyptians, Germans
        Greeks, In. Hans. Massagetes, Persians Romans
        Scandinavians, etc., alike held their sun fes
        tivals, at each of which an offering of the boar
        took place at Yule tide (Yule signifying sun
        wheel). The festival of the Druids in honor of the
        god Thor waa called leul, or Yeol, wher.ee the
        derivation Yule. Christmas was introduced as
        festival as late as the fourth century taking to
        a great extent the place of the old Yule observ
        ance. In other words, what is si ill celebrated at
        Que, n's College, toford; St. John's College Cam
        bridge (Dec< mb. r L 7). and in a few other places is
        but a survival of what was formerly a regular
        and almost universal rite sun worship at the
        winter solstice. h. K. K.
        THE QUIET UFE.
        The Rev. Silas c. Swallow. In a recent address
        in an Indiana church, praised the quiet and do
        mestic type of liTe.
        "Give me," ho said, "the evenings spent at
        home— evenings around the bright fire, the
        father and mother absorbed in good books, the
        children absorbed in innocent games. That Is
        the typical American evening, and I am glad it
        is so common in the West. In the Bast, lam
        sorry to say, it becomes more rare each year
        "It was to an advocate of these quiet evenings,
        a Philadelphian of forty or so, that his gay
        Ife said one day:
        'John, we haven't chairs enough for our
        company.'
        'There are plenty of chairs,' the man re
        plied, 'but too much company.'
        THE BOARS lIKAD CAROL.
        JEM'S KEEP CHRISTMAS,
        Children Demand It on the East
        Side, and That Settles It.
        Santa Claus visited the East
        and hardly missed a
        SS f his hear I I
        cheer of the holiday seasoi
        wu.i a religious significant c to the day for
        he has come to be the patron s=:ii:
        pensed his favors regardless of creed oi
        This meant that tens of tl tie He
        brew children were remembered Just a
        erously as their Italian playmates,
        grounded In the Christian faith from tl
        The Santa Hans v. I
        differs in many respc< ts from th
        man who .u> ts ov< r mi st of 1
        ni-^ht before Christmas with a
        of reindeer. Th Easl E
        long, bushy whiskers, but he carries I
        derful st" re on a pushcart. B
        down through the chimney, either, as 1
        popular gend has him do, for I
        a and wide chimneys in th< i
        He comes up through the steam pipes oi
        the tire escapes of the tenements which are un
        heated.
        Two factors are res]
        of Christmas am. Tit: the Hebrews of tl
        Sid.'. both Christian and i
        workers among the poor. The ItaUai
        upon the day as one of g]
        can. c, and who celebrate it with much
        and receiving of gifts, hav< within the
        years scattered them selves and t>.. ir i
        through the crowded Hebrew distrl I
        fathers and mothers pave Christmas
        dolls and toys to their children,
        youngsters across the hall or in the r.t I
        ement demanded the s:ir:'.-
        The other factor is the growth of S I
        and i barity organisations of i i
        other. The Settlement workers bav< from the
        beginning made rnu. h of Christmas, v.
        laying stress on Its religious signifi.
        out making it a religious issue, they hay*
        upon it as an opportunity fot t<
        lesson of generosity to others I■
        week every Settlement, with the ea
        perhaps, of one or two whi.h are d
        trolled by the most strict" ortl
        had a Christmas tree, a
        of some sort or at least .i distribut
        In the homes of the poor H< I i
        of the well to do, Christmas Is being
        with never a thought that it is th.
        Him w hom th. ir forel
        nineteen centuries ago Tl I
        the stab!.- in Bethlel
        sin, the star In the Easl
        came with rich gifts naturally is not told by the
        Hebrew mothers. Indeed, they have lit)
        no lore about the day to tell their younsjsto rs.
        Many of them have fallen ha, h on tlu
        Claus myth, ami the Hebrew tots arc Jusi
        pleased over It as Christian youngsters ever I
        »TTT. j
        "What stories are you going to tell your chil
        dren on Christinas?" asked a woman connected
        with one of the Settlements the other day of a
        Hebrew mother. The worker was thinking of
        the stories her New-England mother had told
        her long ago. the beautiful stories of the Christ
        child.
        "Tell them stories?" questioned the Hebrew
        mother. "Why should 1 tell them stories? I tell
        them it is the greatest day in the year. They
        pets something for nothing. Ain't that enough.
        I wonder, yet?"
        "Do you believe in allowing your people to
        celebrate Christmas?" a Tribune reporter asked
        an official of one of the big Bast Side syna
        gogues.
        "We encourage th" celebration." he declared.
        "Thrre is no reason why we should not. Christ
        mas no longer has any religious significance. At
        least, it has none in cosmopolitan New-York. It
        will do one no harm to open up his purse once a
        year and give generously where friendship dic
        tates. Indeed, it does a great deal of good, for
        in this generation we are apt to become too
        grasping. Any repression of the Christmas
        spirit would not help us keep our young people
        true to the faith of their fathers. The induce
        ments to become less religious or to slip into an
        other faith are strong enough as it is. If we
        tried to forbid our young folks celebrating
        Christmas they might demand our reasons, and
        that would give the day religious significance in
        their eyes."
        The last week has been a busy one at the vari
        ous Settlements. Several of them have had
        Christmas trees on several successive nights in
        order to accommodate the large number of chil
        dren connected with the various activities of
        the institutions. The present* distributed were
        not expensive, but that did not lessen the ap
        preciation.
        At the University Settlement there Is a guild
        of girls which gives a Christmas party every
        V* -r rbifl y. ar it took the form of a Christmas
        tret- for poor children. Each girl in the guild
        rot only made presents, but gathered bundles of
        and discarded toys from her friends.
        Then they Invited the poorest children they
        cou'J find in the EUvington-st. district and dis
        tributed the gifts among them. The girls of
        the guild took their reward in the form of a
        E cial dar.ee, after a couple of score of young
        su rs bad been sent home extremely happy.
        Grand-sL was the centre of the Christmas
        A VICTIM OF THE FRAY.
        Ants fight •with the tenacity of bulldogs. One*
        they have grappled It Is a tight until one of the
        combatants is killed or so badly maimed U»*t
        It tight longer.
        shopping district on the East Side this year, and
        a great deal of the trading was done from push
        carts. It Is from this fact that many East Side
        youngsters believe thai. Santa Glaus comes with
        a pushcart on Christmas night. The little
        Hebrew youngsters wandered along the streets,
        guziiiS at the beautiful things displayed on the
        cart* which from first to last contained about
        everything one usually find* in toy land. There
        re wonderful dolls to be had for almost noth-
        Jrg. compared with the prices usually charged,
        and the evergreens and holly were much cheaper
        than in other parts of the city. This low scale
        cf prices must prevail, for the Hebrew has not
        leng been accustomed to Christmas outlay, nor
        Is be overburdened with moans.
        The ■tores In Grand-st. and the neighboring
        Streets were decorated as were the stores in
        Other ■bopping regions. There were Christmas
        cards bearing the same inscriptions as those
        distributed by Christian Sunday schools, and
        Windows full of decorative stuff for Christmas
        ti-^.s. Trade was exceedingly brisk for the two
        weeks past, and the majority of the traders
        were Hebrews. This Is of itself a sufficient
        proof that the East Side has adopted Christ
        mas.

        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99021999/1904-12-25/ed-1/?dl=page&q=christmas+carols&sp=25&st=text&r=0.031,0.784,0.283,0.368,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Listen to the music! K Is the Christmas
        fairies einglng to the sick!"
        TMi l the whispered warning with which
        the nwrthm In the 1'niversity settlement dis
        trlct silence their- children Christmas eve. It
        is spoken at the first strain of the song which,
        all through fh Christmas week. Is eagerly lis
        tened for each night at duFk by both old and
        young.
        To the weary ones at the hospital the fresh voices float
        ing In on the night air are heavenly music. To the well ones
        all through the thickly populated district of the yards
        the first carol that pour from the throats of the Christmas
        children is the signal for the opening of a great festival
        In this festival the one-seventh of tfx population of all
        Chicago, which Is gathered In the yards participates, young
        and old alike. Through all the Christmas week the older as
        well as the younger children drink In with simple faith the
        fsnci'-a and legends that center about the Christ child, and
        woml-r with ever fresh delist at that which 1s tinged with
        the weird, the strange, and the mysterious. To these the
        Christmas fairies mean as much and more as the Christmas
        waits of other countries.
        And who. If you please, are the Christmas fairies?
        Choir of Utile Green Elves.
        They are a choir of thirty little children, whose voices
        have heen picked from the Skylarks." the Little Neigh
        bors," and other singing classes attached to the settlement,
        and who have been especially trained to sing the Christmas
        carols. They are dressed like little green elves, with lnng
        rapea and strange peaked caps of green, lined with red trim
        mings that turn back about the face, and with long red
        hoods hanging down behind.
        To the simple folk they are a source of never ending
        wonder and delight. Their queer cortumes, the mystery of
        their appearance Just after the twilight, their spectacular
        dancing aroufid the Christmas tree, with which is opened
        evry night's festivities In the great gymnasium, make a
        wonderful and simple appeal that never loses Its potency
        or effect. Known sometimes as the. singing children." the
        Christmas Fairies are the leading spirit of the Christmas
        mystery, without which no festivities would be complete.
        They touch the button with which the activities bepin.
        It is at the settlement where most of the Christmas ac
        tivities center. Here Is a gymnasium which is equipped with
        a stage where is set up the biggest and grandest Christmas
        tree that can be procured. Every night during the week this
        is lighted and one and another of the clubs, of old and young,
        come here to have their Christmas party. Music and danc
        ing and singing, in which all take part, go on each night.
        The feature of the evening, however, is the entrance of the
        rhich la the signal that the merriment is to
        el Mike fairies.
        begin.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1914-12-20/ed-1/?sp=25&q=Christmas+Carol&r=0.015%2C0.601%2C1.303%2C0.847%2C0&st=text</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        s; after 1 incident a letter
        came saying that a loca! glee club com-
        ??uns: men born ifl England
        led on that hristmas Day to
        rols early in the morning before
        of their friends, thus re-
        ami almost
        ately came inquiries from Sun
        hools and churches about carols
        B t.> be sung at special services.
        ur ago came letter from Mr.
        the Novelle
        house in New York,
        that the demand for carol-?
        ht larger than ever I
        Very delightful was all this to the soul
        e' tin entl inaieal folklorist
        who has had many opportunities in thr
        ef the last decade to note how
        example! of Yuletide music in ai
        garb were winning the-r way in high
        concert rooms. L? r. Krank I)am
        josch set the fashion in this reaped
        liturgical hymns of the
        classic period of ecclesiastical music
        .'limes of the Musical
        ng the chief place in
        irt oi the procramme of the
        of the ?MBBOfl i which al?
        ways r Chi to such
        compc si thr "Hodu- Christas
        trina, Nanini and
        -mas Oratoria" of
        B?ch, some charm.ng French no
        ?uisite
        old German Weihnachtslie
        der b. ..???..nus. Then
        there occurrod to him tl.- BOtiOB of
        a li'tle prelu I pro?
        che simple (."hristmas
        seht, heil'ge Nacht,"
        ?miliar than the Lord's Prayer
        to German children the world over;
        end so he set a custom which has been
        ued by the socit i e.
        \n Sncient Russian <>remon>.
        i have had no public perform?
        ance of English Christmas carols in
        -iiade. 
        A grievous omission.
        Liturgical music of the Russian Church
        i.as been sung for OS by tlie more than
        admirable choir of the St Nicholas
        Cathedral, and to all who love nm-ir
        for the vaiees of boys and men
        to that cathedral in the Russian
        ti sstido, which conies after the
        !?st echoes of ours have died out, is
        haartilj te be neommendeti. A- a a
        nave '?ngs as they arc
        sung now and have been sung foi
        SS by the people of England,
        I 'many, with their ?ng
        of oldtime custon a, so we had
        r twice a hint at a I!
        i* was only h
        this only to the students of
        the historical atid explanatory notes
        provided for the patrons of our bast
        symphor.y concerts. At meetings of the
        Russian Symphony So.
        the Pbi?harmom
        suite by Rimsky-Korsakow, entitled
        performed ander
        'he direction first o. Modest Altschuler
        and afterward o ?riofT. The
        of excerpts from an
        and the portion significa'.? to
        resent parp?se was in the last
        oil sang in
        an ancient sun god:
        1 ke the Koman
        .?lia, the of the
        Winter f<
        I 'ruid?. has been s the
        birth the
        ??val Ralston says in his
        val which h called that of
        ich the influence of the
        Churcl iie extent converted
        bration of the birth of
        '?i have referred in
        ed life uni?
        versally attributed to th.? ana fter the
        gloom of the
        iong nights way to the
        lengthening day. At tha?
        time, according to popular tradition,
        I? being arra\
        holiday robe and head
        hi r ?-eat in her tel?ga. and
        urges BBOB the summer
        ?dar goddess the
        people have given the name of Kolyatla.
        ?nd custom once used to pit m
        'Hif may still be
        kept un, of renresenting her by a fir!
        in white who was seated on a
        ?ledge and driven about from ho I
        while Kolyidki were sung by
        'he >oung people who attended her,
        and who had ?garions presents made to
        'hem m return, such ?gifts being sup
        to hare represente*] thi
        tributiOBS to a sacrifice which used to
        be tnn.lt* m the da\ I of old."
        In on.? of the oldest KolyudkJ which
        have be.mi pie-one,| Mleatial being!
        representetl by the sun. mOOfl Bad stars
        were introdneisd objesHs ef worahip,
        but Mr, RalatOB pointa oui ihnt
        tina conception* were Introduced. Thai
        in Bohemia, Moravia ntid llulgnria "a
        I hristian form bien given to the
        idea. The Virgin Mai y appear?, eithfi
        bathing or washm,; VftstmefltS ifl the
        Jordan? and directly afterward she
        son. anil the angels come and
        cu?v tut uwiiv tu heaven. ?*r shs
        bathes her child and places him Ifl a
        manger, and th doors of a temple are
        I and lights are lit and Christ
        himself serves at the altar The?.
        legentls are not supposed to be ef
        hristian origin, but are looked BBOB
        a? old heathen "lythi to which al'lin?
        tian chat after ha- been given." There
        eial men i the Christ
        mas tima In Rnasia, which lasts until
        Epiphany, rery like those celebrated
        the Christian world o?the songs snng is the "Glory >"Slava">
        which MoussorgskJ ases with such
        thrillinir etTect iti the tinal scene of
        "Moris Godounow" ns i* presentad at
        our Metropolitan Opera House.
        The German Kindclv? legen.
        There ?S On old notion that the fan?
        ciful purpose hrian nun
        strels, the pifferari, in maki g their
        rude music before the ahrinea of the
        Virgin sinally to cas- the laboi
        and that the
        befon
        ph. 
        How much of the dramatic mummery
        of the traditional incidents of the Na?
        tivity bad survived in the I'roti taut.
        churches of I.< ipsic in Bach's time and
        lad hllB 1" pat hil lumber song into
        the "Christmas Oratorio" cannot be
        exactly determined. The little play had
        taken a strong hold on the affections
        of the people, however, and if it was
        BO longer acted, many of the hymns
        which it called forth remained in the
        popular mouth and .some of them got
        into the hymn books. The "lindel
        wiegen" was only one incident in the
        ?iramati?- representations of Christmas
        K\e. .Standing on a platform above
        The CltBSfJ Tree arol.
        Ws ?re in the midst of a r<
        o?her ancient custon,
        of carols. The Morris dance
        coming u.? sgain in I
        and a large collection is mal
        English, Scottish, Welsh and Irish foil
        be old pageant l are on<
        becoming a popular form of
        with .i la m of the i?
        structi.o element, and th.
        da) has exhibited m;
        itiei old and new. An optimist migh
        almost think that the mind of the pe
        pie, weary of the sordidnes- of motl
        ern life and exce??ive I
        art, was turning again to the ?impl
        cei
        old songs anl old en hard t
        lown. The act*- of P
        Puritan days in England could not en
        the caroling and a I
        pit, snd though it
        the singing of enrola wa sil b
        lining of the nin I
        Century, Hone printed the titl
        eighty-nine cato'1; which hsd bee
        printed on broadside In I
        were solt) a?.
        ballad n to be sohl i?i
        ?Square and the neighborhood
        ?o ?Maw York, I
        thine?' connected wil
        ral, the sir.gmg
        origin in Pagan times, an?! wi
        who:; the wintei
        :.ni"r carol
        tor carols have |oil|
        had vogue. A bishop pn..
        in the seventh century from In
        midsummer festivals, 1
        of St. John and other naiir
        would iot tlown, and an Anglo-Saxoi
        irriter of the tenth century, describinf
        .??-vice;; of the da;
        third hour archbishops and minister
        lipped snd moni, observad th?
        hour "mid kyriole and engla lofgt?
        sange" that i I, with irol
        of praise, or laud*. One of th"
        old carols for which Hone exprt
        peculiar affection was "The Cherry
        Tree Carol." the antiquity of which can
        he guessed from the fact that i?
        a par! of the Coventry Mystery, "The
        Miraculous Birth and the Miffs
        preservad In the Cotton MS, i
        warn? Mary of the decree ?if tl
        man Emperor commanding tribute, and
        Mary agrees to fare forth with h
        sufety. On their journey Mary
        rry tree in fruit.
        OB on the Virgin
        purity and ei of Joseph
        jealousy. Naturally, the plain
        it ruder B|
        in the more modern version. As sur
        to the melody printed herewith tl
        words of the carol are as foil"
        v.ont a-wa;'

        rries
        Ha gii.g over yon tree.
        I .I I I i il
        u 1th hi i i weal Los so
        "Pluck those i
        give to my child,
        replie 1 Jo teph,
        o nnkind,
        "I will pluck no cherries
        1 ni to give thy child."
        re
        Be
        rrlts
        By
        'l i uppermost ?prig
        Bowed don n te her knee
        Tbn \ou mi ph,
        These cherries are for rr.e."
        "O eat your eherriaa, Mary;
        0 eat your chert I
        o eat year charrias, Mary,
        '1 hat giow upon li bough."
        do tp'n wa- a-walking
        He heard ?he BBgoll sing:
        .11 be bora
        Our heavenly King.
        'He i ill be born
        In bonee nor in hall,
        Nor m the place of Parad
        But In an ox-stall.
        "He shall not be cloth?.!
        In purple nor pall,
        Bttl nil in fair linen,
        wear all.
        "He shall no! be t o.
        In silver nor gold,
        But in a Wooden cradle
        That rocks on the mould.
        "He neither shall be christened
        In m:lk nor in wine.
        But In pure spr;:ig-we!l water
        i h sprung from Bethine."
        Mary took her Baby,
        She dressed H m so sarna t,
        lid Him in a m i
        All there for to sleep.
        ihn I ?ood over Him
        heard angels sing:
        'i?h, bless our dear Saviour,
        Our Heavenly King"
        Suni* Dutch Christmas Rhyme?.
        Among the customs which the Dutch
        brought from the Natherlnnds when
        they came to found what I
        the Yuletide feet? Itiaa pla*j ed
        on wm
        I I i i
        .i- festival rather than a hriat
        and la I ra
        Nicholas ?Oven Dacembei h?te Iwtlfth
        Nighl .iaiiiirtty i'.. Imritig thia i
        busi-.e*?, waa practically at. a ttaadstill, I
        N'ik
        by the pet di

        tin? lit -ung by the hildren
        fa itival Her? are a few, secern?
        i-. literal translation:
        Sinl Nihlaa go* .1 heilig i
        i an,
        Bpaanjen;
        van Oraal

        it Nicholas, good holy man, put
        far nie
        Brii
        plums from Damaat, give the
        The little
        "Ringel,
        I E

        n.
        i ever do I rug,


        BBS in 't land.

        eh; with h
        S* Nicho?
        las ?mo the i
        III.
        rl\la?s N kkl
        pond ?pikkel,
        Drie
        gek.
        pounds of
        cake, thn of pork, St.
        Nick i
        IV.
        je, bon, bon, baasje,
        me een stukje ?pikhelaa s,
        4ve een i te kosk.

        (Little Baata, -roo.!, geed ?mio man
        nikin, give cake,
        give me ai It 11

        V.
        i'ii.
        mo ri h buil met suikergoed,
        mit te min,
        Bmijl hit BUar ?lea schoornsteen in.
        ,St. Nicholas, good BBBB (blood), give
        me a lu-np of goo,) sugar; not too much
        Bar yet too little; throw it down near
        the chimney.)
        VI.
        Nicola? tiolile baa?.
        Kniipt Wat m niyn BchaCBtje,
        eppeltje of een eitroeatje.
        Baal te Kraken,
        Een pintji- om t.? drinken,
        Dat .al erat beter Uiaken.
        Nicholas noble fellow, bring*;
        someth.ng for iny little shoe. A little
        apple, a little lemon, a. nut to be
        cracked, that hall tasti* riott.-r. a Httl?
        mug to drink from, that shall clink
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042399/1917-12-17/ed-1/?sp=8&q=Christmas+Carol&r=-0.063%2C0.368%2C1.314%2C0.855%2C0&st=text</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>J
              1
              i.'-l.jjk, U'-.J.w. '.t -A
              1AGE EIGHT
              ASHLAND TTDIN'GS
              Monday, December 17, 101 T
              1
              Oregon Moss Agates
              -him mm- 'H in in n i" ii 'in in i rnrtrrf
              Nature's own gem,
              found in the Rogue Riv
              er Valley.
              The stone of original
              beauty.
              Cut and polished in
              wy own lapidary and
              made into jewelry that
              will make a present for
              the most fastidious.
              Your Eastern friends
              will admire it as a sou
              venir of the Great
              Northwest.
              You will find a full line
              of original agate jewel
              ry here.
              IV. B. Penniston,
              "The Mou Agate King"
              THE PLAZA
              Ashland, 4 Oregon
              A Christmas Favorite
              rjlBE toys are to new fanglcd, with
              J their little cranks and
              springs
              fhey make a fellow wonder how a boy
              can run the things;
              you mustn't twist 'em that way an'
              you mustn't far or thake
              Tor fear you'll jolt their innards or a
              dritHn' wheel will break.
              But the jumpin' jack! Be will wriggle
              hit kneet
              An' he'll hump hit bark just at gay at
              you please;
              An' he don't wind up an' he don't run
              town,
              An' hit pantt it red an' hit coat it
              brown;
              Be climbs the tlick with o whark-ty-whuckt
              Boorah for the brave old jumpin' jack!
              Be Isn't quite so, stylish, an' he only
              costs a dime,
              But he it lithe an' limber an' keeps
              busy all the time
              A-bobbin' an' a-noddin' with a caper
              an' a hop
              A-bowin' you a thank-ye when you
              jump him to the top.
              Bo, the jumpin' jack! Be will jiggle
              an' prance.
              An' he'll bend his back like he's doln'
              a dance;
              With his arms 'way up an' hit legs
              'way down,
              An' hit painted grin like a oircut
              clown
              Be slams around with a whaek-ty-whack
              Boorah for the fine old jumpin' jack!
              t reckon fm old fashioned when it
              comet to Christmas toys,
              But wot there any finer thing when you
              an' me was boyst
              Remember him a-grinnin' from your
              ttockln' that-a-way,
              ATI ready to go jumpin' up am' down all
              Christmas dayt
              Bo, the jumpin' jack! Be would wob
              ble hit knees
              An' he'd hump hit back with attonlthin'
              ease;
              Be would jump 'way up an' would sit
              'way down,
              An' he tickled us when he came to
              town.
              Be was best of all in old Santa's pack
              Boorah for the good old jumpin' jack!
              Chicago Post,
              vj4 The Wonderful House c
              S Where Santa Clam
              Ii Dwells k
              Osborn barrows can't be beat,
              Emll Pell.
              rrrouLDy'T you wt to
              rr see the wonderful
              land
              Where Santa C'laus makes
              hit home,
              The magic shops and buildings
              grand
              Filled with toys from cellar
              to dome;
              Where busy thousands work
              day and night
              Making the pretty things
              v Santa Claus gives,
              Weaving into each gift their
              joy and delight,
              In the beautiful home where
              Santa Claut livest
              Over fields of ice, over hills of
              snow,
              It the wonderful home where
              Santa Clout dwells;
              Where love brightens life with
              its eternal glow
              And the blessed song of
              Christmas bells.
              A. Bart Borton in Cincinna-
              ti Commercial Tribune.
              1 Hi
              What the
              Christmas
              "Waits" Sing
              SANTA CLAUS being about to de
              sert tbe city streets tor bis annual
              reindeer ride over tbe roofs, tbe
              "waits" prepare to sing their centuries
              old carols.
              In several American cities bas been
              revived tbe beautiful old custom of the
              "waits" going about from bouse to
              house singing tbe familiar old songs.
              Light tbe Christmas candles In your
              window If you want them to stop be
              fore your borne!
              Qod rest you merry, gentlemen; let
              nothing you dismay
              tbey will surely sing that, perhaps the
              best known of all old English carols.
              And this too:
              Bark! The herald angels ting,
              Qlorv to the newborn king.
              And, of course, "0 Little Town ot
              Bethlehem."
              Perhaps, too, they will -slug what is
              said to be tbe earliest kuown Christ
              mas carol, dating from tbe Anglo-Norman
              days of the thirteenth century,
              which begins
              Lordlingt, listen to our lay
              We have come from far away
              To seek Christmas.
              In this mansion we are told
              Be hit yearly feast doth hold;
              1 'Tit today!
              Hay joy come from Qod above
              To all those who Christmat love.
              This carol ends with tbe toast of
              those days:
              "Here, then, I bid you all wassail,
              cursed be be who will not say drink
              bail." "Wassail" meaning your health
              and "driukbail" being tbe usual and
              courteous acknowledgment.
              One of tbe best known of all the old
              carols, although not one of the oldest,
              was written by JVuhuin Tate In 1703
              and is called the "Soug of the Angels."
              It begins
              While shepherds watched their flocks
              by night.
              All seated on the ground,
              The angel of the Lord came down
              And glory shone around.
              Many are the carols in which Brit
              ain's ancient holly figures. "Then
              drink to the holly berry," pledges one
              writer of songs, while unother In "Un
              der the Holly Bough" summons "All ye
              ed friend or brother, come gather here."
              And then there's that grand old hymn,
              "Adeste Fldelea," sung in every church
              In this land and in others, at this
              Christmas season
              Oh, come, all ye faithful,
              Joyful and triumphant!
              Come ye, tth, come ye to Bethlehem!
              Christmas would not Le Christmas,
              of course, If the "waits" were to neg
              lect one other of tbe most beautiful of
              old carols:
              Boly night, peaceful night!
              Through the darkness beams a light.
              Boly night, peaceful night!
              Through the darkness beams a light!
              .Yonder, where they sweet vigils keep
              O'er the babe who, in silent sleep,
              Restt in heavenly peace,
              Rests in heavenly peace.
              If there are any of you who bave
              in mind an after Christmas dinner even
              ing of song to the accompaniment of a
              harpsichord, a spinet, a lute or a piano
              or even the modern and much adver
              tised disk machine, it might be well to
              try this on the company:
              "Hark th. Herald Angeli Sing."""
              Bark! The herald angels ting,
              Olory to the newborn king;
              Peace on earth and mercy mild,
              Qod and sinners reconciled!
              Joyful, all t'O nations, rise,
              Join Vie triumph of the skies,
              WUh the angelic host proclaim
              Christ it born in Bethlehem.
              Bark! The herald angelt ting,
              Glory to the newborn king!
              Xfl to
              Christmas music
              pi HQ out,
              A. sohercs!
              ye 'crystal
              IK
              our human
              to touch
              II
              Christmat Chimso.
              Ring out, rin? out, oh Christmas bells,
              Across the starlit, frosty night!
              Proclaim Urn message of good will.
              The story of the Prince of Light.
              The centuries roll on and on,
              And yet, returning Christmas time
              Awakes In rich responsive heart
              Remembrance of tke love sublime.
              Then keep the feast with hearty cheer,
              The feast of merry Christmastide,
              While faith and hope and love, these
              three.
              Within the. heart of each abide.
              W. O. Park in Good Housekeeping.
              Bain and Studebaker wagons are
              the best. Emll Pell.
              Once bless
              ears,
              If ic have power
              our senses no.
              And let your silver chime N
              Move in melodious time,
              And let the bins of heaven's
              deep organ lAnt;
              And with your ninefold har
              mony Make up full consort to the
              angelic tymamiy.
              For if such huly snng
              Inwrap our fancy long.
              rime wtu rmnmcu auajeicn
              the age of gold,
              And speckled vu.illy
              Will sicken soon and die,
              And leprous tiiit will melt fV?
              from earthly mold, E
              And hell itself will past away V?
              And leave her dolorous man- fc'C
              tiont to the peering day. tkl
              Yea, Truth and Justice then
              Will down return to men
              Orbed in a rainbow, and, Uke a
              glories wearing,
              Mercy will tit between, V.
              Throned in celestial sheen,
              With radiant feet the tissued Ax
              clouds down steering,
              And heaven, at at tome fes- Jw
              aval,
              'Will open wide the gates of
              her high palace hall.
              -John Milton. 5ft
              Christmas Mystery Plays.
              On their return from the Holy Land
              the pilgrims aud crusaders brought
              new subjects for theatrical representa
              tion, founded on the objects of their
              devotion and incidents In their wars,
              and the early mysteries and other plays
              of Christmas, among them that of 8t
              George and tbe dragon, which has but.
              rived to modem times, probably owe
              their origin to this period.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84029386/1916-12-21/ed-1/?sp=5&q=Christmas+Carol&st=text&r=0.748,1.063,0.383,0.499,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        A Christmas Carol
        By HENRY WADSWORTII LONGFELLOW
        IHEAJt alont our street
        Pass the minstrel throngs.
        Hark! They play so sweet
        On their hautboys Christmai
        songs.
        Let us by the fire,
        Ever higher,
        Sing them till the night expire.
        In Dccemher ring
        Every day the chimes;
        Loud the glee men sing
        In the streets their merry rimes.
        Let us by the Are,
        Ever higher,
        Sing them till the night expire
        Shepherds at the grange,
        Where the babe was born,
        Sang with many a change
        Christmas carols until morn.
        Let us by the fire,
        Ever higher,
        Sing them till the night expire.
        These good people sang
        Songs devout and sweet.
        While the rafters rang
        There they stood with freecing
        feet.
        let us by the fire,
        Ever higher,
        Sing them till tho night expire.
        Who by the fireside stands
        Stamps his feet and sings,
        But he who blows his hands
        Not so gay a carol brings.
        Let us by the fire,
        Ever higher,
        Sing them till the night expire.
        Four Ancient
        Christmas
        Carols
        THE ancient Curlatmng carol
        "Holy Night" la German In lte
        origin and la considered by
        ninny persona to be the most
        beautiful of all Christmas carols. It
        has HometlmeH been ascribed to Martin
        Luther, hut tho consensus of expert
        opinion Is that it Is much older than
        his time anil Is one of the oldest of
        (iciuiun folk songs.
        The enrol "(iod Heat Ye Merry, Gen
        tlemen," Is ICngllsh In Its origin and
        bites bmk to about the beginning of
        the Ni'venteeiilh century, ulttiongh the
        author of the words and the composer
        of the mush; are unknown. The fine
        old melody sung to this poem pos
        sesses all the best qualifications of a
        sterling hymn tune and will probably
        last as long as the verses with which
        It Is always assocluted.
        Originally the old carol was sung In
        polyphonic harmony with the melody
        placed In the t r, ns was the Invari
        able custom of the seventeenth cen
        tury. Modern transcription of It,
        however, have placed tho melody In
        the upper voice part Instead of the
        third voice part, as formerly. Thla
        carol, too, Is one of the most popular
        and most beautiful In the entire range
        of Christmas music
        The carol "Draw Nigh, Immanuel,"
        Is one of the oldest pieces of coherent
        music In existence, and both the words
        and music far antedute any of the
        others. The music Is an old French
        melody, dated from the thirteenth cen
        tury, although, of course, It has been
        harmonized to conform with more mod
        ern standnrds.
        There Is a most curious but beauti
        ful ujusleul effect at the close of this
        enrol. The words of "Draw Nigh. Im
        manuel." are about 100 years older
        than the music, being taken from the
        Mozarablc breviary of the twelfth cen
        tury, and It Is generally believed that
        they were taken from the liturgy of
        the early Christians at Toledo, Spain,
        where the Mozarablc breviary wag for
        mulated. Another carol, "The First Noel," has
        a traditional French melody end prob
        ably originated lu Breton, although tho
        exact origin of this One old eons; la
        somewhat la doubt
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042399/1917-12-17/ed-1/?sp=8&q=Christmas+Carol&st=text&r=0.592,0.353,0.497,0.646,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        A Christmas Favorite
        rjlBE toys are to new fanglcd, with
        J their little cranks and
        springs
        fhey make a fellow wonder how a boy
        can run the things;
        you mustn't twist 'em that way an'
        you mustn't far or thake
        Tor fear you'll jolt their innards or a
        dritHn' wheel will break.
        But the jumpin' jack! Be will wriggle
        hit kneet
        An' he'll hump hit bark just at gay at
        you please;
        An' he don't wind up an' he don't run
        town,
        An' hit pantt it red an' hit coat it
        brown;
        Be climbs the tlick with o whark-ty-whuckt
        Boorah for the brave old jumpin' jack!
        Be Isn't quite so, stylish, an' he only
        costs a dime,
        But he it lithe an' limber an' keeps
        busy all the time
        A-bobbin' an' a-noddin' with a caper
        an' a hop
        A-bowin' you a thank-ye when you
        jump him to the top.
        Bo, the jumpin' jack! Be will jiggle
        an' prance.
        An' he'll bend his back like he's doln'
        a dance;
        With his arms 'way up an' hit legs
        'way down,
        An' hit painted grin like a oircut
        clown
        Be slams around with a whaek-ty-whack
        Boorah for the fine old jumpin' jack!
        t reckon fm old fashioned when it
        comet to Christmas toys,
        But wot there any finer thing when you
        an' me was boyst
        Remember him a-grinnin' from your
        ttockln' that-a-way,
        ATI ready to go jumpin' up am' down all
        Christmas dayt
        Bo, the jumpin' jack! Be would wob
        ble hit knees
        An' he'd hump hit back with attonlthin'
        ease;
        Be would jump 'way up an' would sit
        'way down,
        An' he tickled us when he came to
        town.
        Be was best of all in old Santa's pack
        Boorah for the good old jumpin' jack!
        Chicago Post,
        vj4 The Wonderful House c
        S Where Santa Clam
        Ii Dwells k
        Osborn barrows can't be beat,
        Emll Pell.
        rrrouLDy'T you wt to
        rr see the wonderful
        land
        Where Santa C'laus makes
        hit home,
        The magic shops and buildings
        grand
        Filled with toys from cellar
        to dome;
        Where busy thousands work
        day and night
        Making the pretty things
        v Santa Claus gives,
        Weaving into each gift their
        joy and delight,
        In the beautiful home where
        Santa Claut livest
        Over fields of ice, over hills of
        snow,
        It the wonderful home where
        Santa Clout dwells;
        Where love brightens life with
        its eternal glow
        And the blessed song of
        Christmas bells.
        A. Bart Borton in Cincinna-
        ti Commercial Tribune.
        1 Hi
        What the
        Christmas
        "Waits" Sing
        SANTA CLAUS being about to de
        sert tbe city streets tor bis annual
        reindeer ride over tbe roofs, tbe
        "waits" prepare to sing their centuries
        old carols.
        In several American cities bas been
        revived tbe beautiful old custom of the
        "waits" going about from bouse to
        house singing tbe familiar old songs.
        Light tbe Christmas candles In your
        window If you want them to stop be
        fore your borne!
        Qod rest you merry, gentlemen; let
        nothing you dismay
        tbey will surely sing that, perhaps the
        best known of all old English carols.
        And this too:
        Bark! The herald angels ting,
        Qlorv to the newborn king.
        And, of course, "0 Little Town ot
        Bethlehem."
        Perhaps, too, they will -slug what is
        said to be tbe earliest kuown Christ
        mas carol, dating from tbe Anglo-Norman
        days of the thirteenth century,
        which begins
        Lordlingt, listen to our lay
        We have come from far away
        To seek Christmas.
        In this mansion we are told
        Be hit yearly feast doth hold;
        1 'Tit today!
        Hay joy come from Qod above
        To all those who Christmat love.
        This carol ends with tbe toast of
        those days:
        "Here, then, I bid you all wassail,
        cursed be be who will not say drink
        bail." "Wassail" meaning your health
        and "driukbail" being tbe usual and
        courteous acknowledgment.
        One of tbe best known of all the old
        carols, although not one of the oldest,
        was written by JVuhuin Tate In 1703
        and is called the "Soug of the Angels."
        It begins
        While shepherds watched their flocks
        by night.
        All seated on the ground,
        The angel of the Lord came down
        And glory shone around.
        Many are the carols in which Brit
        ain's ancient holly figures. "Then
        drink to the holly berry," pledges one
        writer of songs, while unother In "Un
        der the Holly Bough" summons "All ye
        ed friend or brother, come gather here."
        And then there's that grand old hymn,
        "Adeste Fldelea," sung in every church
        In this land and in others, at this
        Christmas season
        Oh, come, all ye faithful,
        Joyful and triumphant!
        Come ye, tth, come ye to Bethlehem!
        Christmas would not Le Christmas,
        of course, If the "waits" were to neg
        lect one other of tbe most beautiful of
        old carols:
        Boly night, peaceful night!
        Through the darkness beams a light.
        Boly night, peaceful night!
        Through the darkness beams a light!
        .Yonder, where they sweet vigils keep
        O'er the babe who, in silent sleep,
        Restt in heavenly peace,
        Rests in heavenly peace.
        If there are any of you who bave
        in mind an after Christmas dinner even
        ing of song to the accompaniment of a
        harpsichord, a spinet, a lute or a piano
        or even the modern and much adver
        tised disk machine, it might be well to
        try this on the company:
        "Hark th. Herald Angeli Sing."""
        Bark! The herald angels ting,
        Olory to the newborn king;
        Peace on earth and mercy mild,
        Qod and sinners reconciled!
        Joyful, all t'O nations, rise,
        Join Vie triumph of the skies,
        WUh the angelic host proclaim
        Christ it born in Bethlehem.
        Bark! The herald angelt ting,
        Glory to the newborn king!
        Xfl to
        Christmas music
        pi HQ out,
        A. sohercs!
        ye 'crystal
        IK
        our human
        to touch
        II
        Christmat Chimso.
        Ring out, rin? out, oh Christmas bells,
        Across the starlit, frosty night!
        Proclaim Urn message of good will.
        The story of the Prince of Light.
        The centuries roll on and on,
        And yet, returning Christmas time
        Awakes In rich responsive heart
        Remembrance of tke love sublime.
        Then keep the feast with hearty cheer,
        The feast of merry Christmastide,
        While faith and hope and love, these
        three.
        Within the. heart of each abide.
        W. O. Park in Good Housekeeping.
        Bain and Studebaker wagons are
        the best. Emll Pell.
        Once bless
        ears,
        If ic have power
        our senses no.
        And let your silver chime N
        Move in melodious time,
        And let the bins of heaven's
        deep organ lAnt;
        And with your ninefold har
        mony Make up full consort to the
        angelic tymamiy.
        For if such huly snng
        Inwrap our fancy long.
        rime wtu rmnmcu auajeicn
        the age of gold,
        And speckled vu.illy
        Will sicken soon and die,
        And leprous tiiit will melt fV?
        from earthly mold, E
        And hell itself will past away V?
        And leave her dolorous man- fc'C
        tiont to the peering day. tkl
        Yea, Truth and Justice then
        Will down return to men
        Orbed in a rainbow, and, Uke a
        glories wearing,
        Mercy will tit between, V.
        Throned in celestial sheen,
        With radiant feet the tissued Ax
        clouds down steering,
        And heaven, at at tome fes- Jw
        aval,
        'Will open wide the gates of
        her high palace hall.
        -John Milton. 5ft
        Christmas Mystery Plays.
        On their return from the Holy Land
        the pilgrims aud crusaders brought
        new subjects for theatrical representa
        tion, founded on the objects of their
        devotion and incidents In their wars,
        and the early mysteries and other plays
        of Christmas, among them that of 8t
        George and tbe dragon, which has but.
        rived to modem times, probably owe
        their origin to this period.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id></id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text>
        Christmas Caroling Throughout
        The United States This Season
        Washington preparing for Christmas in the past. The photograph
        shows the trimming of the giant tree in front of the east entrance of the Capitol last year.
        Music Has Real Charm
        To Interest Children
        Fascinating and Interesting Problem To Mold
        Mind and Character of Little
        Ones With Melodies.
        Br J. MarR A
        "We are going to have an enter
        tainment?just tor the little children?"
        piped out a tiny voice In the stree;
        car the other day.
        It may have been for school, it
        may have been for Sunday school. Or
        it may have been at home.
        But how about the kiddies' enter
        tainments? Who chooses what they
        are to say and do?and sing! For no
        "entertainment" is real without
        music, just as no Kiddy party is real
        without ice cream.
        This is a fertile field for bringing
        "music appreciation" to the kiddies.
        FiMiiatlsg Problem.
        It Is a fascinating problem, ton,
        and an important one as well. It
        has much to do with molding the
        minds and the character of the little
        ones.
        A glimpse was given the writer of
        one interesting "music Btudy club" of
        young folks that should extend Its
        influence beyond that small clrcl?.
        The presiding genius was an en
        thusiast, of course, both on music and
        on children.
        I remember out of the hour, the re
        newed impression of the story of "a
        little boy who practiced in an attic.'
        Do you know who it was?
        I wish some one would write me
        that story. We'll print u next we?k
        In The Times' "Music in the Homt"
        pages.
        Many of us do much of our maga
        zine reading through the pictures, do
        we not?
        Practiced la Attle.
        This "story of a little boy who prac
        ticed In an attic" is told In a painting
        that ean be found In the wonderful
        collection of prints at the Public Li
        brary. They can be borrowed, too, by
        a real and serious music club.
        And would you choose a Christmas
        music picture?
        This club had the lovely "Virgin and
        Child" by Piglheln, to paste Into u
        scrapbook record of the music hours.
        The little angel baby facrs that sur
        round the Holy Mother and Babe are
        well worth making friends of.
        Music and painting arc very closely
        allied, these students find. The merry
        god "Pan" Is in many paintings. The
        "pipes of Pan" are the very first in- j
        struments we know about from which
        the wind instruments of the modern j
        orchestra were developed. All this 1
        learned from this club of little folks j
        We sat In an upstairs room, simply
        decorated like nursery, with small
        tables and chairs.
        Chora* Was Sung.
        A phonograph played the Christmas
        music In one corner. We had hearo
        both simple and great music. The
        "Cod rest you, merry gentlemen." out
        of old England; the "Little Town of
        Bethlehem." our own hymn, that
        seemed to tell of the Christmas Day
        when this little Jesus, that Piglheln
        painted, was born into the world that
        we might be better.
        The great "Hallelujah Chorus" was
        sung, just as It will be given here in
        our choral service for Christmas at
        the singing of Handel's oratorio,
        "The Messiah."
        But beyond the music, beyond the
        kiddles, was a crimson glo_v ?>iit
        through the window. The winter sun
        was setting, the room was growing
        dlia. and a few bleak trees against
        all that glow of the w.irm h of the
        wrrld, made one grateful that In a
        quiet corner even today, som.j two or
        three were joined together--brought
        hero by the sweet power of music
        ?but also this Christmas titfe,^ in
        memory of Him.
        Do you belong to a Music Cub?
        Hm anyoaa ?ter invited you to 4
        "music hour" for discovering "How
        to listen to music?"
        If not. seek such an opportunity.
        It will give you Joy.
        And when you meet, read about the
        great composers. Hear the mush.
        And look at some art pictures that
        will tell you the story.
        Your hour will be well spent.
        CHRISTMAS CAROL
        SINGING REVIVAL
        Washington May Follow Other
        Cities in Enjoyable Holi
        day Custom.
        Christmas Eve caroling, through
        the streets of town and city, Is b*>
        J in* revived.
        j Twenty cities of tho United States
        j have arranged elaborate programs
        fr.r sending the OhristMR# message
        j cf song and telbwslili) Into all sec
        I tlons of the co.nmuni'.y.
        Wandering minstrel,, in crimson
        1 cloak', are these modern groups of
        outdoor slngeis, who r? a'^out with
        the belief that Christmas Caroling
        "beautifies community spirit; stlinu
        j lates musical interest; revives a
        charming custom; kindles Christmas
        sentiment." u
        "A carol is a song of Joy. exulta
        tion. praise and devotion. Hence a
        carol expresses the true spirit of
        Christmas as no other class of vocal
        music can.
        "In olden .times, particularly In
        England, it was the custom of child
        ren and young people to sing- carols
        upon street corners, at the doorsteps
        of their friends and in public halls
        In order to inspire within the hearts
        of their hearers, the true meaning
        of the Christmas message.
        "The revival of this beautiful cus
        tom In our country has met with
        hearty response and Is a source of
        much satisfaction to all who believe
        in the ennobling qualities of the
        Christ spirit."
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86091197/1921-12-19/ed-1/?sp=4&q=Christmas+Carol&r=0.11,0.645,0.383,0.249,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              HRISTMAS CAROL
              Music and Song Always Associ
              ated With the Yuletide.
              Original Sacred Character of Carole
              Waa Almost Lost 8ight of in
              Thirteenth Century.
              USIO and song have always been
              associated with Christmas.
              In Roman Catholic countries,
              as early ,as the Third century, It be
              came the custom to usher 1 q the
              Christmas festivities with musical
              masses.
              The practice of singing carols or
              canticles was supposed to recall the
              •jin Excelsis Gloria" of the angels and
              ihe song of the shepherds on the
              first Christmas night.
              A very old carol, published in 1521,
              S ves an amusing description of church
              velrles:
              A wooden child in clouts on the altar sat.
              About the which both boys and girls do
              dance and timely jet,
              And carols sing In praise of Christ.
              The priests do roar aloud!
              And round about the parents stand
              To see the sport, and with their voice
              Do help them, and with hand.
              At first, carols were generally re
              liglous In character, and were written
              ;jvlth Latin and English words In al
              ternate lines, or with a Latin refrain,
              lithe well-known carol
              (When Christ was born of Mary free
              Zn Bethlehem, that fair citle,
              Angels sang with mirth and glee
              In Kxoelsls Gloria,
              and another with a chorus,
              Chrlstua natus hodle
              The babe, the son.
              The holy one
              Of Mary,
              are good examples of this class.
              When the tendency to ribaldry he
              me marked, some of the carols got
              be very peculiar in subject and
              iguage. Joseph is treated with a
              treat want of respect, for one carol
              m
              e
              181
              Joseph was an old man,
              An old man was ho,
              Whon ho wedded Mary,
              The Maid of Galilee.
              Another relates the story of the
              watching their flocks by
              lllght:
              A shepard upon a hill he eatt.
              He had on him hyo tabard and halt,
              jHys tarbox, hyo pipe and hye flagatt;
              Hyo name was called Joly-Joly Watt.
              Having been Informed of the birth
              Of Christ, the shepherd sets off for
              Bethlehem, and on arriving, says:
              Jhesu! I oft Thee my pype,
              S y skyrte, my tarbox and my scrype.
              ome to my fellows now will I skype,
              'And loke unto my shepe.
              In the Thirteenth century the sa
              cred character of these Christmas
              Songs was almost entirely lost sight
              pf. The Puritan parliament abolished
              ISOhristmas and carols altogether, but
              ■feasting and revelry returned with the
              Restoration.
              Carol singing, which had fallen Into
              disuse, was revived by a collection of
              'qarols published by D. Gilbert, In 1822,
              ■but caroling, which was formerly
              ushered In by the chiming of church
              bells, and the sallying forth of choirs
              which chanted their way round vil
              lages until their throats were hoarse
              and their noses red from cold and
              ,frlendly Christmas potations. Is now
              almost a thing of the past.—Tit Bits.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn91068423/1922-12-23/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Christmas+Carol&r=0.328%2C0.121%2C0.832%2C0.468%2C0&st=text</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Caroling Sunday Night and Christmas Tree Mon
        day Night in Union Square Under Auspices
        of Community. Service Where Groups of
        Caroiers Will Assemble Tomorrow.
        With the season's shopping sched
        uled to end before midnight. the
        Christmas season, already a busy one
        irom a trade standpoint will onfm-
        into anotner phase Christmas mncif.
        and sermons, distributiion of food and
        ciothing among the poor and a eeneml
        j remembrance of one's friends or the
        less tortunate. The weather, to judge
        irom the samples yesterday and to
        day, will be ideal.'
        Chief events outside of the churches
        tomorrow and Monday will be:
        Distribution by the Rotary club Sun
        day afternoon of baskets to the poor
        of this city and vicinity.
        Singing of -carols beginning Sun
        day night at 8 o'clock by children
        under adult leaders in all parts, of
        Hickory and adjourning towns. i
        Christmas tree on Union
        square
        Monday night
        rri i
        me caroling and t hristmns trpf
        will be under the direction of Com-
        munity service, of which Miss Mar-
        gueri
        .ite nson -is director. Mrs. S.
        iir:i. i.
        H. Farabee is chairman of the carol
        ing general group and a dozen com
        petent women are group chairmen and
        leaders.' Mrs." R. S. Brown, director of
        music in the Hickory schools, drilled
        the children in the carols.
        Christmas Tree
        The Community Service committee
        for Christmas have been busy for
        several weeks -refecting plans for an
        Everybody's Christmas and Tree of
        Light to be held at 7 p m. on Christ
        mas day.
        Promptly at n n. rn. the Carolers
        at the -Tree will start singing H6iy
        iNignt as Mr. VV. J. Shuford presses
        the magic button which will light the
        star on the very ton of th trep a
        short address of welcome by Mr. W,.
        A. Self will then follow. THp TTipVorv
        Band will play a few selections and
        the full colored lights for the entire
        tree will be turned on and Every
        body's Christmas Tree will be Hick
        ory s and yours. The caroling groups
        will then sing "II came unori the
        midnight clear" and "O Come All Ye
        Faithful," after which ali are invited
        to come up and View the tree h bit
        oser. s
        The Community service organiza
        tion is a new one in Hickory but is
        demonstrating the. "aluie of uisitecl
        civic effort in such Community cele-
        brations as this Christmas program.
        The caroling will be a new Jh'
        for Hickory but according to the in
        terest displayed this year is should be-
        ome an unusual event in which large
        grovjps participate. Parents are asked
        to accompany the children whenever
        possible in the caroling and thus acid
        to the general interest.
        The tree was secured and will be
        erected" by the CavalVyr troop under
        the direction of Captain Earl T. Ed
        wards. The lighting wa contributed
        by the Southern Public Utilities com
        pany. Notice to Children
        Children attention! Did you hann
        your naine to Mrs. Brown in school
        saying that you would like to sine
        Christmas carols on Sunday evening
        between 8 and 9 p. m We are looking
        for you then at one of the group
        meeting places. Every one is urged to
        assemble promptly in order that no
        one wishing to welcome the carolers
        hall be dissapnointed. Arrangements
        have been made for sixteen groups
        and at least 20 should sing in each oA
        these groups.
        All children should go to the group
        headquarters nearest their home.
        A list ot the places where, the caro
        ers will assemble follows:
        Ward 1 Mrs. George Baily, chair
        man.
        Brookford There will be four
        groups under the direction of Mr.
        Hainey which will start out from tlu
        church and cover the entire town of
        Brookford. TH Carolers in Brookford
        are to start out at 6:00 p. m. in order
        to finish the caroling before the even
        ing service at the church.
        Longview There will He iwa
        groups caroling at Longview, they
        will meet at the Baptist church and
        go out from there.
        Monday's Program'
        All groups of carolers are' asked
        to meet on Christmas day, Monday
        at Union square, at 6:45 p. m. "The
        Tree of Light" which is- everybody's
        tree will be lighted for the first
        time at 7 p. m. ar the caroling groups
        are asked to sing at the tree. The,,
        program will be. short lasting .not
        over '45' minutes.
        Be sure to have your lighted candle
        ready on Sunday evening at 8 "sharp
        to welcome the caroling groups for
        the carolers will sing only before the
        homes showing the symbol of wel
        comed Christmas c'ommittee Mrs. S. H
        Farabee, general chairman, Mrs. Rob
        ert Brown, schools and music, Mrs.
        George Bailey, Mrs. Harold Shuford,
        Mrs. R. J. Revely, Miss Emma Bon
        ner, Mrs. W. J: Shuford, music at
        the tree and band.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89060136/1925-12-04/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Christmas+Carol&r=-0.187,0.348,1.456,0.947,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        By JOHN DICKINSON SHERMAN
        IS THE Christmas Carol com
        ing back to its own as a
        time-honored feature of the
        Christmas Tide? It looks
        so. And it Is to be hoped
        that it is so. For the sing
        ing of Christmas Carols will
        WvyirJ help to popularize the religi
        ous observance of the day—
        which is losing ground year by year in
        this material age.
        Probably there is no room in our
        Twentieth Century civilization for
        carol-singing after the old way. But
        carol-singing on a large scale is ad
        mirable —as many American cities
        abundantly proved in 1924. It was
        made a community service. Many
        singers were enlisted and trained.
        Carols were sung in hospitals, orphan
        ages and other institutions. The mes
        sage of home was carried to the travel
        er in hotels and railroad stations.
        Mass-singing In municipal auditoriums
        was received with popular acclaim.
        This community service was strangely
        reminiscent of the old-time “Waits”—
        street muslcluns who were an estab
        lished institution of English cities,
        weurlng “Walts badges,” with the
        town arms.
        The singing of carols Is much older
        than Christmas, just as the midwinter
        festival of good cheer long antedates
        the celebration of Christmas as the
        anniversary of the birth of Christ. The
        pagan Britons celebrated this midwin
        ter festival; so did the Jtomuns and
        many European peoples. It was not
        until the Fourth Century that this fes
        tival became identified with the church
        festival of Christmas —“Christ-mass."
        Have you discovered that it’s very
        easy Indeed to dance to some of the
        Christmas Carols? Well, It is. And
        that’s because “Carol” was originally
        a term for a dance —or for songs In
        termingled with dancing. It was a
        long time before- the word came to
        be applied strictly to a religious
        Christmas song.
        Primitive man makes merry, you
        know, in song and dance and boister
        ous play. It is not hard to see in the
        Christmas of modern times plain evi
        dence of the pagan origin of mid
        winter festivities. The “Yule Log”
        undoubtedly spread from the ancient
        Lithuanians and Letts, whose “Christ
        mas Eve” was “Log Evening.”, The
        “Lords of Misrule” of England was n
        leftover from the Roman Saturnalia
        The Christmas Carol goes back a
        long way into early English life. The
        first printed collection came in 1521
        from the press of Wynkin de Worde.
        This early master-printer was prob
        ably born in Lorraine and went to
        London to be assistant to Caxton.
        whom he succeeded la XUfl. It Is inter
        esting to know that a fragment of this
        edition is still extaitf and contains the
        famous “Boar’s Head Carol,” which
        is stilt sung on Christmas Day in
        Queen’s College, Oxford —whether the
        serving of the boar’s head on a silver
        platter in the big dining hall still ob
        tains, one is not prepared to say.. In
        the old days the serving of the boar’s
        head, with much pomp and ceremony
        and minstrelsy and song wns the
        feature of the Christmas feast in the
        homes of the wealthy and great. The
        authentic wording of this carol is as
        follows:
        The boar's head In hand bear I,
        Bedeck'd with hays and rosemary;
        And I pray you, my masters, be merry,
        Quot estis In convivio.
        Caput aprl defero,
        Reddens la'udes Domino.
        The boar's head, as I understand,
        Is the rarest dish In all this land,.
        Which thus bedeck'd with a gay garland
        Let us servlre cantico
        Caput defero, etc.
        Our steward hath provided this
        In honor of the King of Bliss,
        Which on this day to be served Is
        In Reginensl Atrio,
        Caput apri defero, etc.
        At the time Wynkin de Worde pub
        lished the first collection of Christmas
        Carols in 1521 carol-singing was a uni
        versal practice in England. In 1525,
        when Henry VIII lay ill, there was on
        edict specifically prohibiting “carols,
        bells or merry-making.” In 1526 a
        license was issued to Thomas Trysdale
        to print, “Certayne goodly Carowles to
        be songe to the Glory of God.”
        The Puritans endeavored to put a
        stop to carol-singing and practically
        succeeded. Parliament, It will be re
        membered, ordered the abolition of
        Christmas Day and to show that It
        had been abolished sat in session
        December 25, 1652 —“commonly called
        Christmas Day.”
        But Christmas day came back with
        the Restoration—and so did the Christ
        mas Carol. In 1661 appeared a volume
        with the title, “The New Carols for
        the Merry Time of Christmas, to Sun
        dry Pleasant Tunes.”
        In France also the Christmas Carol
        is very old. The French word for the
        Christmas Carol is Noel. The Breton
        word is “Koroll,” which means a dance.
        Soel originally meant “birthday.” In
        There was a long pause when noth
        ing was accomplished.        
        time it came to mean the “Birthday of
        Jesus.” Still later it was a song about
        His birthday. Nowadays a Frenchman
        wishing anyone “Merry Christmas,”
        says, “Joyeux Noel!’’
        Now the title. “The First Nowell,"
        of the English Christmas Carol, from
        which quotation has been made in the
        foregoing, throws a sidelight on his
        tory. This carol.is probably more than
        500 years old, although it did not ap
        pear In print until 1533. The Norman
        conquest of England was responsible
        for the “Noel” in its title. And this
        in turn was changed to “Nowell” to
        make it look English and to insure its
        pronunciation in two syllables.
        “Silent Night” is probably one of
        the most popular of all the Christinas
        Carols. It seems to have been first
        published in Leipsic as a “Tyrolean
        Song.” Before that It had been in
        the repertoire of a family of strolling
        Tyrolean players. Its origin was then
        unknown and it was said to be old.
        In time it was credited to Michael
        Haydn. A few years ago Ludwig Erk
        made a thorough investigation and re
        ported that “Silent Night” was written
        and composed in 1818 at Oberndorf,
        Germany; that Joseph Mohr, assistant
        priest, wrote the words; that Franz
        Gruber, a schoolmaster, wrote the
        music. According to Erk, the carol
        was produced Christmas Eve in the
        church, the poet, a tenor, singing the
        melody, and the composer singing
        bass. A chorus of young women sang
        the refrain. The church organ was
        out of repair and the accompaniment
        was played on a guitar.
        “God Rest You Merry Gentlemen”
        is believed to date back to the Seven
        teenth Century. It certainly Is as
        familiar to the English-speaking world
        as any. One version has the first line,
        “God Rest You Merry, Gentlemen”—
        one does not know whether or not the
        use of the comma is authorized.
        It will be noted that the Christmas
        Carols in general have a common char
        acteristic—which Is especially promi
        nent among the older ones: They are
        set to pleasing and not dlflicult music;
        they are simple in form and pic
        turesque; they are often childlike in
        their naivete. In short, they are real
        bits of folklore.
        Yet men famous In the world of
        letters have not disdained to try their
        hands at the Christmas Carol. For
        example, “O tittle Town of Bethle
        hem,” deservedly popular, was writ
        ten by the Boston divine, Phillips
        Brooks. It was intended for Sunday
        schools only. Several composers have
        written music for it. These include
        Joseph Burnaby, the Englishman, and
        Louis H. Redner, the American.
        </text>
      </result>

      <!-- Additional queries-->

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87062169/1928-12-21/ed-1/?sp=5&q=christmas+hymns&r=0.452,0.368,0.519,0.338,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        “Christmas Hymns
        and Caro/s”—No, 3
        Christmas wouldn’t be Christman
        without these fine old songs of the
        season. Every year they cast their
        spell over youngsters and grown-
        ups alike. Here is a Victor record
        ing by the famous Trinity Choir,
        who sing many of the old favorites
        for you. This week’s release also
        contains several of the big songs
        from recent motion picture produc
        tions. Come in and hear them all—•
        this week!
        Christmas Hymns and Carols—
        No. 3—Hark I the Herald Angela Sing
        —Christians, Awake I—Holy Night—Oh#
        Little Town of Bethlehem—Hallelujah
        Christmas Hymns and Carols—
        No. 4—Calm on the Listening Ear—It
        Came Upon the Midnight Clear—Naza
        Teth—Star of Bethlehem—Oh, Come,
        All Ye Faithful Trinity Choir
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038485/1924-12-21/ed-1/?sp=64&q=christmas+carol&r=0.08,0.429,1.307,0.85,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        CHRISTMAS CAROLS
        Carol, Brothers, Carol,
        Carol joyfully;
        Carol the Good Tidings,
        Carol merrily,
        And pray a gladsome Christmas
        Far all good Christian men;
        Carol Brothers, Carol,
        Christmas Day again.
        Christmas in lands of the fir tree
        and pine,
        Christmas in lands of the palm tree
        and vine,
        Christmas where snow peaks stand
        solemn and white,
        Christmas where cornfields lie
        sunny and bright—
        [Everywhere, everywhere, Christmas
        tonight!
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86061215/1908-12-24/ed-1/?sp=6&q=christmas+carol&r=-0.58,0.128,2.161,1.405,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99021999/1909-12-12/ed-1/?sp=10&q=christmas+carol&st=text&r=-0.041,0.057,0.919,1.195,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Christmas Hymnology
        A Literature to Which Christiana of All Denomination! Hare Con
        tributed and in Which People of All Faiths Are Interested.
        O
        N ('HIllSTM AH day In the year
        1.106 dlrd Jaropo del Renedettl,
        the author of the "Stabat
        Mater." It 1 tiot generally
        known that this singer was the
        author of a Christmas carol
        written In the aame strain an hi beautiful
        liymn for Passlontlde. It rutin thin:
        81a hat Mater apeciosa
        Junta foenum gaudiosa
        Dum p:;rbat. parvuius
        which Dr. J. M. Neale rend""!:
        Full of hrauty stood the Mot!ir
        fcy the mangel, beet o'er other,
        Where her little one she lays.
        It lit a pathetic incident In connection
        with this "arol that Its author breathed
        his last on the holy night of the Natlvltjt
        s the choir win chanting the old C'hrlat
        nias carol "Gloria In Kxcelsis" In the
        (hutch clone by. Mis last words were
        Jesu nostra fldanza." lie was burled In
        the cenif-tery of the Minorites at Calloione,
        and on hit tomb I inscribed "Stullus
        piopttr C'hrlKtm nova mundutn arte delimit
        et caelum rapult."
        It Is st mime that while Ilt-glnald Heber
        t as actually engaged In the compilation
        of a "Church Hymnul" at the time that he
        waa appointed bishop of Calcutta, neither
        Ills Kaster hymn nor his Christmas carol
        finds a place In the "Church Hymnal."
        And yet the following verses serin sin
        gularly suited to a money making age like
        t ho present:
        If gayly clothed and proudly led.
        In dangerous wealth we dwell,
        Remind us of Thy manger bed
        And lowly cottage cell.
        to our sorrow, but still he Is human," says
        the Post. "Can he be thrown off like a
        mall bs or must he be reasoned with and
        Induced to tarry by the wayside? Does he
        lose his rlirhts as passenger towvrd a com
        mon carrier berause his skin Is Mled with
        alcoholic refreshment? And where is the
        point at which he Is Intoxicated New
        York Tribune.
        If prest with poverty severe,
        In envious want to pine.
        Oh. may the Hpirlt whisper near,
        How poor a lot whs Thine.
        'I he most ancient Christmas hymn In the
        "American Church Hymnal"' is that by
        Aurellus Clemens Prudentlus. who was
        born In fpaln and was a very distin
        guished Jurist In hla day. It Is rendered
        by Dr. Neale:
        Of the Father's will begotten
        Kre the worlds began to be.
        ilia hymn found under those assigned
        (or the Epiphany Is also a Christmas carol,
        beginning:
        Earth haa many a noble city
        Bethlehem thou dost all excel.
        The English version of tne hymns Is by
        an American hyninologist, Kdmund Cas
        well, to whose pen we are Indebted for
        tlie carol, "Com hither, ye faithful,"
        which cannot be traced further back than
        the close of the sixteenth century, al
        though it haa an ancient ring about it
        which would place II much earlier. Father
        oakley, who left the Church of England
        at the time of the Tracturian movement,
        has given us a carol running very much
        In the same strain. "Oh, come, all ye
        faithful, Joyful and triumphant," which oil
        account of its spirited refrain is one of the
        most popular Christmas hymns.
        John Byrom, a poet and essayist of some
        distinction, who lived In Manchester, Ens
        land, from ltffll to 1IW, and whose aged
        daughter, the present writer, had the honor
        of meeting in her home in Deanagate of
        that city about 18MS, is the author of what
        ia probably the best of the Christmas
        songs: v
        Christians, awake, salute the happy morn
        Whereon the Saviour of mankind was born.
        Mr. Byrom's "Private Journal and Cor
        respondence" are of peculiar Interest, for
        he was not only a scholar., but a man of
        wit and 'observation.
        Two well-known Christmas carols In tho
        "Church Hymnal" are from the pen of a
        Unitarian minister. Dr. Edmund Hamilton
        Hears, a man of a devout and spiritual
        mind and a graceful and vigorous writer.
        The, first Is the popular hymn beginning:
        It came upon the midnight clear
        That glorious song of old.
        And the other begins:
        Calm on the listening ear of night
        Comes heaven's welcome strain.
        The beautiful carol so popular In both
        school and home which Dr. Phillips Brooks
        wrote as he stood In tha fields of Bethle
        hem and looked down on the little city,
        will live In history. There Is nothing
        finer bi the whole circle of Christmas
        -.-arols:
        Oh. little town of Bethleliem.
        How still we see thee lie;
        Above thy deep and dreamless sleep
        The silent stars go by;
        Yet in thy dark streets vhlnetli
        Tha everlasting light.
        Another American clergyman who has
        given us a good Christmas carol is Dr.
        Augustus Muhlenberg, the founder of the
        Church of the Holy' Communion, New
        York; Ut. Luke's hospital and the set
        tlement at St. Johnsland on Long Island.
        Its spirited refrain makes It very popular:
        Hhout the glad tidings, exultlnglv sing
        Jerusalem triumphs, MesHiah Is Kin;!
        There are two more carols by American
        authors, Mrs. Alexander's "Once In David's
        Royal City," and John Cawood's "Hark,
        the Hound of Holy Voices."
        Fifty years ago the great Christmas
        hymn was that by Charles Wesley. In
        fact, no Christmas day was celebrated
        without It. Its strains are still familiar:
        Hark the herald angels King
        'jlory to the new born King.
        Hut this ell known hymn is antedated
        by that from tha pen of Kahum, TatX
        who was poet laureate of England when
        he wrote It In the year 1703. The poor
        poet died in a debtor'a prison In South
        wark In 1715, when "devout women not a
        few" were alnging hymns In the churches
        close by.
        Charlotte Elliot, the bedridden poetess,
        who has given us "Just as I Am," has
        also bequeathed to the church a Christ
        mas carol. "Thou Didst Leave Thy Throne
        and Thy Kingly Crown."
        One of the best carols of the Elizabethan
        period Is that by Robert Southwell, a Jesuit
        priest who was sent to convert England,
        but who was seized by her Protestant
        majev.cy Elisabeth and Imprisoned In the
        Tower for three years, and then after suf
        fering the tortures of the rack was exe
        cuted February 22. 15M. It begins:
        Behold, a simple tender Babe
        In freealrg winter night;
        In homely manger trembling lies,
        Alas, a piteous sight.
        During the protectorate of Oliver Crom
        well the observance of Christmas was for
        bidden and yet there Is a Christmas carol
        from the Puritan pen of George Withers
        who was enriched and promoted by Crom
        well and thrown Into prison by Charles, li
        b6irs:
        As on the night, before this happy morn i
        A blessed angel unto shepherd (old.
        Bishop Christopher Wordsworth of Lin
        coln lias given us the hymn beginning
        "Hlng, oh sing, this blessed morn!" Miss
        Elliott, tho author of "Just As I Am."
        wrote "Thou didst leave Thy throne and
        Thy kingly crown." James Montgomery,
        w To was considered one of England's moil
        eminent poets by no less an authority than
        Lord Byron, Is the author of tho carol
        beginning "Angels from the realms of
        glory."- Montgomery was born of Moravian
        parents and dedicated to tho ministry, but
        he took up newspaper work Instead and
        became eminent In general literature as
        will as In poetry.
        Faul Gerhardt. to" whom we are Indebted
        for the Easter hymn Jesus Lives." has
        also plven n a spirited Christmas carol
        beginning "All my heart this night rejoices."
        In the midst of the warlike strife he
        tween King Charles and his parliament in
        the year l2it John Milton found both
        leisure and repose to write his hymn, "On
        the morning of the nativity," In which
        there tie evidently references to the dis
        turbed conditlor. of things at that time,
        e. g.:
        No war or battle sound
        Was heard the world around.
        In the compilation of those Christinas
        odes the true catholicity of "the theology
        oi uymns is evident, for among their
        w i Iters are two English bishops, oneJrishop
        of the Americai church. Roman t'athollc
        monks and prlesta. Unitarian ministers,
        Moravians and Lutherans; In fact he
        whole circle of Christian believers has been
        searched in order to express In the service
        of song the Joys and the peace of Christmas
        tide.        
        
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn92053934/1909-12-25/ed-1/?sp=6&q=christmas+carol&r=0.221,0.35,0.292,0.19,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>

    </results>

  </topic>

  <topic>

    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-adolph-luetgert</id>

    <results>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87060190/1897-05-18/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Adolph+Luetgert</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Adolph L. Luet
              gerjl, a well known manufacturer vraa
              arrested yesterday afternoon on tho
              chargo of having murdered his wife.
              Luetgert made an assignment about 10
              days ago, and about tho same time Mrs.
              Luetgert disappeared. It was at first
              supposed that she had committed sui
              cide, as a result Of her husband's
              failnro.
              Tho river was dragged, but with no
              result, and for several days detectives
              have been working on tho murder
              theory. Tho police claim to have direct
              evidence that Luetgert klljed his wife
              in tho basement of his sausage factory
              in Diversoy street, and that her body
              was destroyed with the object of hiding,
              all traces of tho crime.
              Tho police will show, they say, that
              Luetgert persuaded his wife to accom
              pany him to his sansago factory on Aie
              evening of May 1 that upon gettiug
              into his building ho choked her to death
              or to insensibility that he then threw
              her into a vat containing a powerful
              acid, and completed his work by casting
              the body into an intonso firo.
              This is the direct chargo against tho
              prisoner. Tho main evidence in snp-
              Jiort of it aro two gold rings which be
              ouged to Mrs. Luetgort and which
              were found by the polico in a vat in tho
              sausage factory. Ono of tho rings
              found in tho vat was tho wedding ring
              of Mrs. Luetgert.
              On tho day following tho woman's
              disappearance Luetgert failed in busi
              ness, and tho sheriff took possession of
              the sausage factory. Luetgert endeav
              ored time and again to gain udmission
              to the factory but tho deputy sheriffs re
              fused to admit him. The polico claim
              that he desired to get into tho place for
              the purpose of removing all traces of tho
              crime. Ho did attempt to olean out
              tho vat in which the rings were found,
              but tho escape pipe was a few inches
              abovo the bottom of tho tank and the
              rings sank to tho bottom below tho level
              of the pipe.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82016014/1897-08-07/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Adolph+Luetgert+wife&st=text&r=-0.14,-0.064,1.28,1.28,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Luetgert was calm and composed
              when he was brought into court and
              he had apparently been greatly re I
              freshed by Sundays respite from the
              daily court room ordeal Assistant
              States Attorney McEwan formally
              opened the case for the state Op the
              wall close to the jury box were hung
              large maps of the Luetgert sausage
              factory the Luetgert home and all the
              surroundings of the place where it is i
              charged the prisoner killed his wife
              and then destroyed her body The at il
              torney for the state began with the
              disappearance of Mrs Luetgert on May
              1 and next described the visit on May
              4 of Dietrich Blcknese brother of Mrs
              Luetgert when he called to see his sis
              ter and discovered that she had disap
              peared 
              Mr McE wan said it is the theory of
              the state that Mrs Luetgert accom
              panied her husband into the factory
              between 1036 and 11 celock About
              1030 her little son Louis returned from
              the circus and saw her sitting In the
              kitchen The conversation of the boy
              with his mother was interrupted by
              Luetgert who came in and ordered the
              boy to bed Before going to sleep the
              boy heard his father descending the
              back stairs toward the factory where
              he had slept for years Mr McEwan
              said it is cite theory of the state that
              Mrs Luetgert descended the stairs at
              the same tim andwent to the factory
              The boy did not hear her steps because
              she wore house slippers which made no
              noise Luetgert and his wife were seen
              in the alley in the rear of the house a
              few minutes later They were seen
              gong through a gate which led tb no
              place except the factory
              ALLEGED MOTIVE
              The alleged motive and operating
              I reason which actuated Luetgert ac
              cording to the theory of the state was
              then described Mr ileEwon said Luet
              gert despised hs wife He had treated
              her with violence as the evidence of
              the state will show He had no affection
              for her and lived alone in the factory
              There the attorney said he had been
              visited by other women Judge Vincent
              objected to this statement but Judge
              Tuthill overruled the objection Mr
              McEwan paid a witness would testify
              that he KUV Luetgetri choke his wife in
              the chicken house back of the resdence
              She said
              You need rot toll me as you did that
              man for I have no money
              This caused Luetgrert to say that she
              would rot be allowed to betray him
              I Then the afternoon session began
              the first witness called was Diedrich
              Bicknez brother of Mrs Luetgert He
              told the jury of his visit to the house
              of Luetgert on May 4 to see his sister
              There he met the sausage maker and
              talked with him for some time before
              he was informed that Mrs Luetgert
              had disappeared Bicknez said Luet
              gert told him he did not know what
              had become of his wife He had last
              seen her at S oclock the Saturday
              evening previous Luetgert said he did
              I not believe she had gone away with
              i some other man but thought she had
              wandered away The witness said he
              asked the prisoner what he had done
              to find his wife and was Informed that
              he had rot told the police of her dis
              appearance Instead he said he had
              paid two private detectives 5 each and
              they would do more than the police
              would accomplish
              I The witness said Luetgeri told him
              he had not looked to see if his wife
              had taken any clothing with her ex
              cept the dress she had on when he last
              saw her He had not visited any place
              or made any inquiries
              I I Bicknes told hyi story in i a simple
              I straightforward way that made him an
              impressive witness
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1897-08-31/ed-1/?sp=6&st=text</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Continued from Page I
              had gone to a circus on the evening of
              his mothers disappearance He re
              turned about 1030 and found his
              mother to whom he described what he
              had seen at the circus While engaged
              in this conversation he said his father
              entered the room and ordered him to
              I bed Later lIe said he heard his
              father descending the rear stairway in
              the direction of the sausage factory
              This portion of his testimony was
              identical with that given at the pre
              liminary and the habeas corpus hear
              ings
              But today he continued by saying
              that after he had been asleep for a
              long time he was suddenly awakened
              byhearing a rustling of skirts in his
              bedroom He called out Is that you
              father but his mothers voice replied
              I
              plied no it Is me
              The lad declared that he was sure
              that it was his mothers voice which
              replied to his query and he soon went
              tQ sleep
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>hhttps://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063952/1897-10-23/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Adolph+Luetgert+wife&st=text&r=0.29,0.43,0.184,0.207,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Last night Luetgert mndo the fol
              lowing statomunt under oath:
              "To tho Public Tho result of ny
              trinl Is a victory for mc becauso of the
              disagreement of tho Jury, but 1 nm
              very much disappointed nnd very
              much surprised thnt tho jury did nut
              bring in a verdict of not gulltv.
              "1 did not kill my wife, nnd do not
              know whoro she Is, but I nm sure thnt
              It is only a question of timo until hIio
              comes home.
              "I did not jjo vpon tho wltnoiw
              stnnil because my lnwyor. Judge Vln
              coiit, wns bitterly opposed to my do
              ing so, and W'iinsc- he ndvUed me it
              was not necessary. 1 nm grntoful tor
              the tremendous change In publio boh
              tiincnt In my favor, nnd time will
              demonstrate that I nm not only nn in
              nocent, but n very grievously wronged,
              mnn. Adoi.imi I LrirrnriiT."
              "Subscribed nnd sworn to before
              mo this Slst day of Octobor, A. 1).,
              1807. F. M. Suu.iVAX, Notary Public."
              "Yes, sir, wo will try him ngnlu,"
              said Suite's Attorney Dencon, whoit
              asked ns to probability of Luetgert
              being brought before tho court n sec
              ond tlmo. "When xve will get at him.
              however, Is something I cannot toll
              you now. We have had nine weeks of
              this, and I must have a couple of
              weeks' rest After that wo will look
              tho ground over and get our evidence
              together."
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85033781/1897-10-27/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Adolph+Luetgert+wife+witness&st=text&r=0.05,0.702,0.208,0.234,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>CRIME Of A CENTURY
              Review of the Celcb'ittd l.iot
              gert Murder Trial d
              Chicago.
              SCORES OF WITNESSES EXAMINED
              tate Wearfi a Net of Circumstantial Evi
              dence About the Prisoner Expert Teatl
              loony uu Hone Foil ml in the Middle Vat
              of the SauMtge Factory Allege! Appear
              ance or the MUliitf Woman In Varloin
              Place Perwoiiallty of the Prioner.
              Or the rJfiht of May 1 last Louisa
              Luetgert disappeared. At 8 o'clock
              Mary Siemmering. the servant girl, re
              tired for the night, leaving Mrs. Luet
              gert Etill about the house. A little later
              the boy Louis returned from a circus
              vhich had been exhibiting in the neigh
              borhood and found his mother sitting In
              a chair. It was then about 10 o'clock
              end he was sent to bed, having seen the
              last of his mother, perhaps forever. Mr.
              Luetgert came Into the house a little be
              fore the boy went to bed, and the latter
              left husband and wife together. At this
              roint the story diverges and the most
              erious trouble of A. L. Luetgert's life
              begins. At what hour Mrs. Luetgert
              left the house no one, save possibly her
              husband, knows. The following day
              Sunday members of the family knew
              that its mistress was gone. On the 17th
              day of May the climax came. The saus
              age maker, who had been almost a king
              among his neighbors, was dragged up
              the steps of the East Chicago avenue
              police station at about 2 o'clock In the
              afternoon.
              Luetgert's preliminary examination
              began before Justice Kersten on May
              22. Bickenese, Mrs. Luetgert's L. other,
              told of Luetgert's indifference, old
              Frank Bialk told how Luetgert had
              spent the night on which his wif dis
              appeared cooking something in the rrii
              die vat, and the police disclosed the
              rings. Mrs. Agatha Tosch, Luetgert's
              warm friend and proprietor of the sa
              loon which he patronized most, declared
              to the police she believed him guilty
              cf wife murder, and unexpectedly went
              on the stand and told how Luetgert had
              railed about his wife to her, and had
              eald he wished she were dead.
              The only person from whom the po
              lice could not extract a word was Lust
              gert himself. Sweatbox, persuasion,
              threats and coaxing had no effect on
              him.
              One Week to Get a Jnry.
              The trial was begun eight weeks ago,
              on Aug. 23. One hundred and forty ven
              Jremen had to be summoned, and one
              "week consumed before twelve Jurymen
              were secured. On Monday, Aug. 20,
              Diedrich Bicknese, the first witness for
              the prosecution, was put on the stand
              Louis Luetgert, the 12-year-old son
              cf the prisoner, was one of the state's
              earliest witnesses. He recited the oc
              currences of the night of May 1, and
              told a powerful story for the prosecu
              tion, on cross-examination there was a
              rurprise for the state. The boy an
              nounced that at 2 o'clock in the morn
              ing of May 2, when, according to the j
              ytate, Mrs. Luetger's body was being
              destroyed in the vat, he heard a "rust
              ling" in the house, and a voice which I
              he believed was his mother's. Young i
              Luetgert acknowledged he had suddenly
              recollected this in the office of Luetgert's
              attorneys, and the state flatly charged
              that Luetgert's attorneys had manufact
              ured the evidence.
              Luetgert's threats, his statement that
              he would like to cru?h his wife, and that
              he regreted calling a doctor for her
              when she was ill, that the "dead, rot
              ten boast would have croaKed," were re
              counted by Mrs. Agatha Tosch. Frank
              Bialk told of Luetgert's unexplained
              actions the night his wife vanished, and
              then the state disclosed how the potash
              came in the vat.
              Frank Odorofsky and Jacob Lavan
              dowsky, two laborers about the factory,
              told starring stories of breaking potash
              Into small pieces, burning their hands
              and faces, and putting it In the vat un
              der Luetgert's orders. They described
              the sticky, slimy stuff on the basement
              floor the morning after the alleged mur
              der, when Luetgert had partly flushed
              the vat by means of a hose.
              Had Hitter Quarrel.
              Neighbors and relatives of th Luet
              gerts testified to the bitter quarrels be
              tween them, and Luetgert's employes
              related how Mary Siemmering, his serv
              ant, had visited him at the factory at
              unseemly hours. It was known that
              when Luetgert sent old Frank Bialk to
              a distant drug store for Hunyadl water
              while he was busy at the vat, there were
              fifty bottles of Hunyadl water in the
              factory.
              Emma and Gottliebe Schimpke, two
              girls living across the street from the
              Luetgerts, went on the stand and told
              cf seeing Luetgert and his wife going
              In the direction of the factory at 10
              o'clock on the night of May 1. Luet
              gert's attorneys succeeded In frighten
              ing them on cross-examination. There
              was a second sensation when Nicholas
              Faber testified that on the night of May
              1 he had gone to Luetgert's house to ap
              ply for work at the factory, and that he
              also had seen Luetgert and his wife go
              ing down the alley toward the factory
              !oor.
              The gold rings, with Mrs. Luetgert's
              Initials, were regarded as the strongest
              vldence the state produced. Numer
              ous witnesses, some of whom had worn
              the rings, positively Identified them as
              Mrs, Luetgert's, and but one witness
              was ever produced who doubted their
              authenticity.
              The state began by showing the feel
              ing of Luetgert toward his wife. Then
              the prosecution traced her from the
              house on the night of May 1 almost to
              the door of the factory with her hus
              band. It was shown that the basement
              door was barred, and that Bialk, thdi
              only person In the factory that night,
              had been sent away at about the time
              It was charged the rnWder occurred.
              Hone Identified a Human.
              Odorofsky and Lavandowsky disclosed
              Luetgert had caused the furnace to be
              raked out the following day, and It was
              where these ashes were dumped that
              parts of the fragments of alleged hu
              man bone were discovered.
              A sesamoid bone and a metacarpal,
              badly mutilated by the fluid, and found
              In the middle vat by the police, were
              positively Identified as human by Dr.
              Dorsey, a curator at the Field Colum
              bian museum: Dr. George V. Bailer,
              working osteologist at the museum, and
              Dr. Howes, an articulator. Another
              fragment of bone from the heap
              where the furnace Takings were
              dumped was Identified as -part of a hu
              man t.kull. A badly mutilated bone from
              the engine room was Identified positive
              ly by Dr. I)or.y as rart of a human
              thigh bone, and from the size of these
              fragments the experts expressed the be
              lief they were from the same Individual,
              and that individual probably a woman.
              Luetgert's attorneys caused two en
              tire human bodies to be cftoked In the
              middle vat and rarte of several others,
              to see whether V'de Pta?h would de
              stroy them as the state claimed.
              Corsetmakers identified the steels
              found In the furnace raklngs as corset
              steels, and 'rom the bony fragments the
              experts lcVf'flcd the head cf a human
              rib, a seconu piece of thigh bone, and
              a fragment of a human toe.
              A to the Hone.
              William Charles, Luetgert's closest
              friend, positively stated he. had helped
              Luetgert dump four barrels of tallow
              and bones In the vat on the night of
              May 1 to make soap with, and other
              witnesses confirmed the claim of the
              defense that Luetgert was making soap
              on the night of May 1.
              Since Luetgert's arrest the claim has
              been made that Mrs. Luetgert has ap
              peared In at least 100 different cities,
              from Nebraska to New York city. Some
              of these were Investigated, and In ev
              ery case but one the defense's assertion
              was exploded. That was the defense's
              claim that Mrs. Luetgert was seen at
              Kenosha, and in the opinion of the state
              It was never shown Mrs. Luetgert was
              there. As many witnesses, and more
              reputable ones, saw the strange woman
              there and were sure she was not Mru.
              Luetgert.
              In all.over 200 witnesses testified dur
              ing the eight weeks of the trial. The
              total cost Is estimated at 118,000.
              Dlversey.
              Differ on Jlulnet Plan.
              Luetgert and his wife had widely dif
              ferent notions as to how large a saus
              age plant ought to be built. Luetgert
              had visions of a six-story building,
              with railroad tracks running to It and
              loaded cars at the doors. Mrs. Luetgert
              wished her husband to Invest $40,000 In
              the new plant and the balance of their
              savings In some other investment.
              Family Jan Increased.
              Last February Luetgert's factory
              closed down. When profits ceased to
              pile up Mrs. Luetgert's scoldings and
              the family Jars Increased. Mary Siem
              erlng had In the meantime come to live
              with the Luetgertfj. and Luetgert's fond
              ness for her, It V said, Increased the
              bitterness between him and his wife.
              Financial roi stared Luetgert in the
              face by the middle of April. The sausage-maker
              and his wife saw that the
              factory was almost certain to pass Into
              the hands of the sheriff, for note9 were
              falling due, there was no Income to pay
              them from, and butchers and market
              men who were In Luetgert's debt were
              unable to help him out of difficulty in
              the hard times. Mrs. Luetgert, who
              had seen her advice thrown to the winds,
              and her dire predictions all come true,
              lost no opportunity to scold her hus
              band for his folly. The reports of the
              Luetgert family disturbances Increased
              throughout the neighborhood and were
              the object of many conferences among
              Mra Luetgert's relatives.
              S17EABSHE ISSIHLESS
              First Sworn Statement Made by
              Adolph Luetgert, the Alleged
              Chicago Wife-Murderer.
              BRIEF DENIAL THAT HE IS GUILTY
              Did Not Kill III Wife and Doe N6t Know
              Where 'Site 1, lie Kay Uelleve She
              Will Yet lleappear Alive-Jury Fail to
              Agree, Declare Agreement Impolble
              aud I DUc barged Accused Mail Will
              Try to Get Out on Hail.
              Chicago, Oct. 22. The Associated Press
              last night obtained the one great feature
              missing in the famous Luetgert trial
              the sworn testimony cf the defendant
              himself, Adolph L. Luetgert. Standing
              last night In the gloomy Jail adjoining
              the grim-looking gray-stone court build
              ing in which his remarkable triaj had
              at last been brought to a finish, the burly
              sausage manufacturer capped the cli
              max of the extraordinary series of events
              which began with his bankruptcy and
              alleged frightful diabolism cf boiling his
              wife to death at midnight in a vat In his
              factory cellar. Closely following the
              final result of the trial which has at
              tracted world-wide attention, Luetgert
              made under oath a statement concerning
              the fearful crime charged against him,
              the first sworn statement of such a kind
              ever known In newspaper annals.
              Few If any of the curious prisoners
              and turnkeys who were' spectators had
              any inkling of what was taking place.
              Luetgert, the notary and the representa
              tive of the Associated Press conferred
              together for a few moments and then
              Luetgert without hesitation made affi
              davit and signed It In ink with the hand
              that Is alleged to have committed one of
              the most fiendish crime on record.
              "I Did Not Kill My Wife."
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1897-12-10/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Adolph+Luetgert+wife&st=text&r=0.679,0.225,0.343,0.386,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>LUETGERTSVIFE SEtN IN BOSTON
              Startling Declaration Made
              By a St Louis Man
              r
              GAVE HER REASONS
              FOR LEAVING HOME
              U
              It Was Because of Luetgerts
              Actions With Other Women
              Mr Schofield the Man Who Tells
              the Story Gives the dumber cf
              the Residence On tho Boston
              Street In Which Hrs Luetgert
              Stopped and She Had ITo Hesita
              tion In Acknovr1 edging Eer Iden
              tity Believes Her Still in Boston
              Boston Dec 9Th Globe says Mrs
              Luetgert the supposed victim of the
              sausage manufacturer murderer so
              called in Chicago is alive and well
              Mrs Luetgert was seen in this city
              during the month of July acknowledg
              ed her identity besides giving more or
              less explanation relative to the reasons
              which caused her to leave her husband
              who is again to be tried for his life
              Such was the startlirg declaration
              made by John Schofield of St Louis
              to a Globe man
              Mr Schofield supplemented this
              statement further with the positive assurance
              surance that Mrs Luetgert was at tha
              hcuse No 7 Bullfinch Place for a period
              iod of three or four days during the
              middle of July last He said he gained
              the assurance on the fact that Mrs
              Luetgert while in Boston acknowl
              edged tier identity with the assurance
              that she left her husband because of
              his actiors with other women as well
              as for reasons which she thought would
              helD him in his financial embarrass
              ment in business He further asserted
              that he believed Mrs Luetgert was still
              in Boston and that she would yet be
              found
              The Globe has interviewed Mrs Moss
              of No7 Bullfinch Place who says that
              the woman supposed to be Mrs Luet
              gert went by the name of Millie
              Barker One day the woman seemed
              distressed after reading an account of
              the trial of Luetgert and when ques
              tioned by Mrs Moss said
              You would be surprised if I told you
              who I am
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063615/1898-01-22/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Adolph+Luetgert+wife&st=text&r=0.035,0.562,0.183,0.206,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>When were jou married the second
              time7" Luetgert was asked bj' his counsel.
              "In" 1STS. to Louise BIcknose."
              There was not a trace of emotion In ther
              voice. of Luetgert as -ho mentioned the
              name of the woman he Is charged with
              having murdered.
              Luetgert proved to Imj a, vty laihrjmose
              witness, his fears coming frequently and in
              considerable volume whenever the name of
              his dead wife was .brought into ther case.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1898-02-10/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Adolph+Luetgert+wife&st=text&r=0.794,0.427,0.161,0.181,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>SAUSAG MAKER
              WAS CONvcnD 1 l
              Luetgert Jury Brought In a l
              Verdict of Murder 1
              1
              WITH A SENTENCE OF
              LIFE IMPRISONMENT
              Jury on the First Ballot Were
              Unanimous for Conviction i
              1
              On the Exception of the Verdict J
              Luetgert Laughed Does Not R
              gard It Seriously and Is Confident J
              cf a New Trial and Acquittal l J
              1few Spread Like Lightning 1
              Motion for New Trial E
              tered
              Chicago Feb 9Adolph L Luetgert
              was tonight convicted of the murder
              of his wife and sentenced to Imprison
              ment in the penitentiary for the term
              of his natural life
              Luetgert received the verdict with a
              laugh
              VERDICT SURPRISED HIM
              At first Luetgert refused to say any
              thing his one response to questions be
              ing I wont talk about It At length
              he yielded to inquiries enough to say
              that the verdict was a surprise to him
              I dont see how the evidence justified
              such a verdict but one thing is sure
              the supreme court will give me a new
              trial and I shall be acquitted  
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88053055/1899-07-28/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Adolph+Luetgert+wife&st=text&r=0.397,0.54,0.295,0.331,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>LEUTGERT DIES IN HIS CELL.
              Chicago Lawyer Declares the tfanaage
              Maker Confessed Wife Murder.
              Joliet, Ills., July 28.—Adolph L.
              Luetgert, the wealthy Chicago sausage
              maker, who
              in the penitentiary here for the mur
              der of his wife, was found dead in his
              cell yesterday. Doctors Werner and
              O'Malley held a post mortem examina
              tion, disclosing tho fact that Luetgert
              died from fatty degeneration of the
              heart.
              Frank Fay Pratt, a member of tho
              Chicago bar, said last night that
              Adolph Luetgert confessed in Febru
              ary, 1898, that he had killed his wife.
              "He told
              Mr. Pratt. "He started to tell me some
              of the details, but fell to cursing about
              the affair and I was unable to lead him
              back to an unfolding of the steps of
              the crime.
              serving a life sentence
              lie had killed her," said
              "I was connected with the Chris.
              Merry defense, and in my visits to my
              cliont I became acquainted with the
              sausage maker. 
              'Yes, that i
              I did kill my wife.
              I was possessed of the devil and killed
              her bee
              in love with
              other woman.' He then started to tell
              1 I
              about the vat, and said his wife
              attempted to make a dying statement
              to him when the dogs began to growl
              and be put
              that he switched off to cursing. As
              I considered the confession
              sional
              end to her. It
              then
              profes
              T respected it until death
              placed him beyond further
              a
              has
              human pursuit."
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn91068084/1899-08-04/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Adolph+Luetgert+wife&st=text&r=0.656,0.413,0.291,0.327,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>A week after her sudden disappear
              ance her brother asked the police to
              investigate. The police searched the
              factory. They drained a large vat
              filled with strong acid. At the bottom
              they foun,U two gold rings, one of which
              was inscribed with Mrs. Leutgert'
              Initials; some steel corset stays and
              a bone of a woman's foot. This was all
              that was ever found of tho missing
              woman.
              Leutgert made a hard fight in court.
              His first trial resulted In a disagree
              ment, but at his second trial be was
              found guilty of the murder and sen
              tenced to the penitentiary.
              </text>
      </result>

       <!--Additional queries--> 

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063034/1897-08-31/ed-1/?sp=1&q=sausage+king+adolph+leutgert</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        The trial of Adolph
        gert, the sausage maker, for the al-
        I, ~1 murder of his wife on May 1, began
        j. irnest to-day. Two witnesses were ex
        amined—Died rich Bicknesae, brother of
        j tr Leutgert, and Louise Leutgect, the
        L->car-old son of the accused.
        Th testimony of Bicknesae tends to
        show the alleged indifference of Leutgert
        to the fate of his wife and the alleged dis.
        ii nation to report the matter of her
        disappearance to the police department.
        Louis Leutgert, who is a remarkably
        bright lad for his age, produced something
        of a sensation in concluding his testimony,
        m l it is believed caused counsel for the
        prosecution to regret having placed him on
        the stand. The boy testiiied that his
        mother came to his bedroom after ho had
        retired and some time after he heard his
        father descend the back stairs going to
        the pantry.
        Contrary to the expectation of the state,
        tin jury i!l bo asked by the defense to
        witness an experiment in the basement of
        the sausage factory. This is to be the
        result of an experiment conducted by
        J. attorneys Saturday and yester
        day. The body of a man of about Mrs.
        i.uolgert's age and weight, who met his
        death by violence Thursday, was taken
        to the factory at 60! University avenue
        end immersed in a solution of potash. The
        result exceeded their expectations. The
        ns rciatid that after ladling the lardy
        j:i a :.o per cent, solution of potash for the
        e inn length of time, three and one half
        nears, and under the same circumstances
        the .-late alleges Luetgert disintegrated
        tin body of Ills wife, the complete skeleton
        of tin- cadaver remained in the vat intact
        or I iliai the solution had had but little
        efil'd on ihe clothing. Asa result of the
        test the defense will, it is said, ask Judge
        Tu nili to remove his court and the jury
        to the basement of the big sausage fac
        es' for a few hours and witness another
        experiment, which the defense claims will
        comi'ieteiy disprove the slate's theory of
        disintegration.
        La igert was calm and confident when
        brought into court, and he has apparently
        b"*n greatly refreshed by Sunday's re
        from the daily court room ordeal,
        bedrid State's Attorney McKwan form
        al op. :.1 the case for the state, and on
        t.i' wall dose to the Jury box were hung
        J irgr maps of the Luetzgert sausage fae
        'i. i Luetgert home and all the sur
        i landings of the place where it is charg
        ed the person killed his wife
        men destroyed her body. The attor
        1' for the state began with the dls
        ai'i'.ira of Mrs. Luetgert on May 1,
        ad n.-xt described the visit on May 4 of
        lu iri ii Hi knesse. brother of Mrs. Leut
        a o lie called to see his sister, an.l
        1 own 1 that she had disappeared. He
        and i :i on tli.. apparent indifference of the
        n i his statement that he had not in
        i ani' I tin police, but had hired two de
        and his invitation to Blcknesse to
        'in in about a week, when he would
        u'm if anything had been discovered
        "i rning the whereabouts of iiis sister.
        '"'r.ey McKwan told the jury that
        1 la. ri s statement that he bad hired
        v\.. de ti tiv< to search for his wife would
        be proven false.
        'li Al -Kuan said it is the theory of the
        b 1 that Mrs. Luetgert accompanied her
        1 i->in.l i.T.o the factory between 10:30
        e 11 o’cl." k. About 10:30 o'clock Louis
        oil' 1 from the city and saw her sit
        in the kitchen. The conversation of
        ">th his mother was interrupted
        i- igert, who came in and ordered the
        1 i<> bed. Before going to sleep the boy
        1 1 bis father descending the back
        toward the factory, where he had
        tor years. Mr. MclOwan said it is
        11 orv of the state that Mrs. Luetgert
        and the suits at the same time and
        'o the factory. The boy did not hear
        s -ausi she wore house
        made no noise. Luetgert and his
        w< re si. n in the alley in the rear of
        louse a few minutes later. They were
        e .iiig through a gate which led to
        exi pt the factory.
        attorn' for state then declared the
        ii.. ins ot I.uetgert in tlie factory, the
        g on of the steam to the vat, the
        ot Watchmen Blckaee shortly
        a drug store und Hlcksae's suhse
        i rand to the drug store all of which
        m o,| t of the factory for an hour
        ill'. He was away when Mrs. Luet
        r* ,H l<>*t se. n alive In the alley.
        u .'l-.ged motive and operative reason
        ictuate 1 the accused Luetgert, ac
        lo the theory of the spate was
        ■scribed. Mr. McKwan sual I,uet
        l sposed of ills wire. He had treated
        1 violence as the evident s' for the
        "ill show. He hud no affection for
        l lr 1 lived done in the factory. There.
        am y says, he had been visited by
        1 j' r "omen.
        V l nt objected to thg statement
        jl Tut hill over-ruled the objection.
        "al.l U witness will testify he
        I inert choke his wife in the house
        !lil f. sldence. Him said-. "You need
        is you did lhal man, for I
        rnon- y." This iusr*l Luetgert to
        Wls hot to lie allow' dto betray
        f inccnt objected, to this state
        i reign to i ami not prop
        hut he was ox fcr-ruled by the
        M' l.w un cone Aided. Attorney
        I iunowned that i*o address would
        I d presintf The, first w itness was
        IJnsfe of the city
        and. testified to file correctness of
        "v on the bt.ard used by th-j
        Hi .ii,
        t •fiernoon Mi ssion began, the
        Cl wus l.il' drleh Blcknesse,
        1 Jury of his visit to the
        f' t 1
        1 *'*T the suusage maker
        b.. w ‘tn nir for some time before
        "Hie,| ii ha, Mrs. Luetgert hast
        i kn<>Sse said i.uetgert
        '"d tot know what ha0,. IJt, hllll last SI ep her
        1 lit previous, Luetgert
        hi I h believe she had gone away
        r mate hut thought slie
        iisuty The wlluem said lie
        prisoner wimt he had
        t Und his wife an,| |f
        r I lSold lie lis t paid two
        r*■ each and they would
        Xo poliws Mould W'.'.vmpdsli,
        JUnftting ffeto£
        The witness said I.uetgert told him he
        had not looked to see if his wife had taken
        any clothing with her except the dress
        ahe had on when he last saw her. He had
        not visited any place or made any in
        quiries. Bicknesse told his story in a sim
        ple, straightforward way that made him
        believed by many.
        Louis Luetgert. 12 years old, the bright
        faced son of the woman, was called. He
        told more than on the former occasion,
        but the statement of the boy ivhieh caused
        the state to regret that he was a witness
        for the prosecution was that at midnigh
        or later, long after the time when the
        murder occurred, according to the theory
        of the state, he heard his mother's voice
        in the house. The boy said he attended
        a circus on the night of May 1, and re
        turned home at 1:30 o'clock. There he
        found his mother sitting in the kitchen,
        in a house wrapper and slippers, reading.
        He told her what he had seen at the cir
        cus, but his conversation with his mother
        was interrupted by hts father, who came
        into the kitchen and ordered him to bod.
        Before he went to sleep he heard his
        father descending the back stairs, as if
        going to the factory. Hts mother he did
        not see again, and the next morning he
        saw that her bed had not been slept in.
        The testimony did not differ from the story
        told by the boy on former occasions, but
        to the surprise of the state, he made the
        declaration that some time in the night,
        long after he went to bed, he awoke and
        heard a rustle in his room.
        “Is that you. father?" he said; but his
        mother’s voice replied:
        "It is me.” The boy said he was sure
        it was his mother's voice. Assistant
        State’s Attorney McEwan asked him why
        he had not told this before.
        He said no one had asked him about it.
        “I asked you if you had heard your
        mother after you left her in the kitchen,”
        said the attorney for the state.
        “I thought you meant if I had seen her
        again," was the boy's reply.
        The defense refused to cross-examine
        the boy, and the court adjourned for the
        day.

        
        
        
        
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026355/1898-01-22/ed-1/?sp=1&q=sausage+king+adolph+leutgert&r=-0.136,0.006,1.105,0.719,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Chicago, Jan. 21. Adolph L. Luet
        gert went on .the witness stand today
        and told to the Jury the story of the
        doings In his sausage factory tho night
        of May 1. Ho endeavored to explain
        the mystery surrounding the disap
        pearance of his wife, for whoso murder
        he Is being tried. An immense crowd
        gathered around the criminal court
        building, but the police only allowed
        those to enter who had tickets of ad
        mission. Judge Gray's court room was
        packed some time befor the opening
        hour. There was an unusual number
        of women present. The audience paid
        the closest attention to Luetgert's ex
        amination. Prior to going on the wit
        ness stand Luetgert, while taking ex
        ercise In the Jail, was accompanied by
        James Smith, who has been on trial
        with Chris Merry for tho murder of
        Merry's wife.
        Smith was extremely nervous over
        the outcome of the Jury's deliberations
        in his case, but Luetgert spoke en
        couragingly to him.
        "I received an invltntlon to a mas
        querade ball which takes place on Feb.
        said Leutgert. "I'll let you have
        it. You'll be able to use it before I
        will."
        After relating the story of the various
        financial deals in which he was inter
        ested, Leutgert was asked If during
        the time he was first engaged In busi
        ness he was married. To this Luetgert
        replied in the alllrmnttvo. "I was mar
        ried to Miss Pauline Ruelke in 1872,"
        said he.
        "How do you spell that name?"
        "I don't know: I never could spell
        it," wus Luetgert's reply.
        Attorney Harmond, of counsel for
        the defense then went Into Luetgert'H
        financial affairs at the time ot Mrs.
        Louisa Luetgert's disappearance, and
        drew out the statement that Luetgert
        was worth ubout $90,000, exclusive of
        real estate.
        Attorney Harmond then asked Luet
        gert when his first wife died.
        "In November, 1877."
        "And how long vvere'you a' widower?"
        "Until January, next year."
        LEUTGERT WEEPS.
        At this point Luetgert broke down
        and commenced crying like a child.
        Seeing the condition of his client, At
        torney Harmon asked for a recess, but
        Judge Gray refused to allow It, and
        after a few moments Luetgert regained
        control of himself.
        "When were you married the gerund
        time?"
        "in 1878, to Louise Blcknese."
        Theie was not a trace of emotion In
        the voico of Luetgert. as he mentioned
        the name of the woman he is charged
        with having murdered. The defendunt
        then told of the various places he and
        his wife had lived, and of his going
        Into business at his latest location In
        1870.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84023058/1897-08-31/ed-1/?sp=2&q=sausage+king+adolph+leutgert&r=0.208,0.617,0.847,0.551,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Chicago, Aug. 31.—The trial of Adolpfl
        Luetgert for wife murder began in earn
        est yesterday.
        Luetgert was calm and confident look
        ing when brought into céurt, and he had
        ‘apparently been greatly refreshed hy
        Sunday’s respite from the daily court
        room ordeal.
        District State Attorney McEwan for
        merly opened the case for the state. On
        lthe wall clase to the jury were hung
        large maps of the Luetgert sausage sac-.
        tory and the Luéigert home and sur-|
        mundings. 
        The first withess called was Dledrich
        Bicknere, bréther of Mrs. Luectgert. He
        told the jury of his visit £6 the house of
        Luetgert May 4 to see His sister. There
        he met the sgusage maker and talked
        with him for s&?‘wﬂm‘e before he'was in
        formed that Mfa, Bmetgert had disap
        peared. Bicknere said Luetgert told
        him he did net knew:what had become
        of his wifé. He had Jast seen“her at 8
        o'clock tife oa,'&rg@, xening previous.
        Lustgert daid #e digtigt Belitve she had
        gone away with: qqueother man, but
        thoug®™ she hag Wdhdered away., The
        witness said Hesasied theprisoner what
        he had dgne to fudihig Wife and was in
        formed that heia® notitold the police of
        her dtsapmap%e. Ingtead, he said, he
        had .paid vabe d’oteitdveso $5 each,
        and they would do more than the police
        would ‘“W ?e withess said
        Luetgert told hith he'hpd not looked to
        see if his wife hafl:talkten any clothing
        lwith her extept the dresis she had on‘i
        when he last saw her, He had not visited
        any plach oy xade any inquiries-
        Bicknere told his story in a simple,
        straightforward way that made him an
        impressive witnegs.
        Louis ILetgerf ,the 12-year-old som
        of the accused, followed Bicknese on the
        witness stand.
        Louis Imetgert, who is a remarkably
        bright lad for hig age, caused something
        of a sensation in concluding his testi
        mony, and it is believed made the coun
        sel for the prosecution regret having
        placed him on the stand. The boy had
        already been examined twice as to his
        knowledge of his mother’s disappear
        ance, dnd in %?ther case did he yefer ta
        having hearqﬂ'e 8 mot Her about the houss
        after he Hid Been gént to bed,
        Yesterda¥ he recounted how he had
        gone to a eoftélis oh the evening of his
        mother's disaPpearance, He returned
        home aboyt 2 fg‘&ﬂ_ﬂ found his mother,
        to whom be d%6&fbed what he had seem
        at the ciréuls. While engaged in this
        conversation, he satd, fils father entered
        the room and ordeted éu;n to bed. Later;
        he said, he heard his father descend
        ing the rear stairs in the direction ot
        the saus:‘%e—factory‘ This portion ot
        his testimOny was identical with that
        given at the pPeliminary hearings bi’
        he continire@ by saying that after he
        had been asleep for a long time he was
        suddenly awakened by hearing a rust-|
        ling of skirts in his bedroom. He called
        out: “Is that you father?’ but his
        mother’s voice answered: “No, it’s me.”
        The lad declared that it was his
        mother’s voice which replied to his query.
        and he soon went to sleep. The state’s
        attorney aslted Louis why he had not
        told this part of his testimony before,
        and he replied that no one had asked
        him if he had seen his mother after re
        tiring. The defense refused to cross
        examine the‘boy._z
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042303/1899-07-28/ed-1/?sp=1&q=sausage+king+adolph+leutgert&r=0.493,0.426,0.563,0.366,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063592/1897-10-05/ed-1/?sp=1&q=sausage+king+adolph+leutgert&r=0.079,0.155,0.585,0.38,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>

    </results>

  </topic>
 
</topics>
